<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vfi1 on Lewwwk</title>
    <link>https://lewwwk.com/tags/vfi1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vfi1 on Lewwwk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lewwwk.com/tags/vfi1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the Frontiers – A simple guide.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venturing on the frontiers is about the early stages of taking on big challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s a space where conventional models to planning and management prove ineffective. It&amp;rsquo;s the place where entrepeneurs trust their &amp;lsquo;gut&amp;rsquo; and face the challenges with an unrelenting push forward. And it&amp;rsquo;s the place from which the greatest change can come about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giddy-up: getting better on the frontier.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Coming out of this first inquiry I&amp;rsquo;m left with new definitions for venture, venturing, and venturer and also a simplistic grouping that the process of venturing essentially requires agreement, action, and governance. It is important to note that these are a set of observations and interpretations that will continue to be evolved in practice. As such they represent a starting point for a concerted effort to &amp;lsquo;get better at venturing and investing on the frontiers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gettin’ it goin’ without goin’ under: cohesion and incipient instability.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
With requisite attention being held a natural propulsion will emerge.  The act of managing and nurturing that propulsion is attended to with a focus on cohesion and being proactively aware of the emergence of incipient instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts are addressed in depth in Stafford Beer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;viable system model&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/higlights-from-of-enterprise-viable.html&#34;&gt;my reflections here&lt;/a&gt; on reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Enterprise-Classic-Beer/dp/0471948373/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1199076860&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Heart of Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;) and are really about holding the tension between future (vision), and here and now (operations) [see last post for &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/12/venturing-on-frontier-requisite.html&#34;&gt;more on requisite attention&lt;/a&gt;]. Cohesion has a lot to do with articulating purpose as so well described by[ ]{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration: underline;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_C._Collins&#34;&gt;Collins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_Porras&#34;&gt;Porras&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://harvardbusinessonline.hbsp.harvard.edu/b02/en/common/item_detail.jhtml?id=410X&amp;amp;referral=2340&#34;&gt;Building Your Company&amp;rsquo;s Vision&lt;/a&gt;. And incipient instability is about monitoring trends in financials, plan performance, and relationship status (after all, ventures are systems, concentrated bundles of relationships), and then spotting changes that indicate that something is becoming instable in a way that could harm the cohesion of the system as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the frontier: requisite attention</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Venturing on the frontiers requires distinctly holding attention on two discrete aspects of any venture:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Productive, iterative, exploration of the complexity dynamic&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Core venture viability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple to say but in practice, venturers who aren&amp;rsquo;t stuck in perpetual analysis and thought, are pulled toward focusing on linear, or hopefully exponential, growth of the most promising aspect at hand particularly after attracting professional investment capital. Stop thinking and just do it right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics of the frontier: complex ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The frontiers of venturing are the places where conventional venturing and planning approaches become least effective. It is the effective limit of conventional approaches to venturing that define the edge of the frontier with the deepest depths of the frontier being the pre-concept stage of a systemically focused venture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831.jpg?v=0&#34; title=&#34;Frontiers of venturing&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 10px 10px 0pt 0pt; float: left; width: 286px; height: 265px;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
Conventional approaches loose effectiveness the earlier a venture is in the development phase because of increasing ambiguity.  The less that is known the harder it is to do linear modeling and planning.  Choices made continually reduce ambiguity as the venture moves along the development and into the realm where conventional planning approaches can be effectively used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the frontiers – Inquiry #1wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-inquiry-%231wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-inquiry-%231wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A little over a year-ago I began considering &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post3&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s next in my journey&lt;/a&gt; and exactly 3 months ago I &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post29&#34;&gt;initiated my first inquiry&lt;/a&gt; into what&amp;rsquo;s needed on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post40&#34;&gt;frontiers of venturing and venture investing&lt;/a&gt;. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a linear journey of course, with a good deal of my attention going towards getting &lt;a href=&#34;http://causeway.socialfinance.ca/&#34;&gt;Causeway&lt;/a&gt; going over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that was ongoing, I had about a dozen conversations over November and December with some extraordinary social venture investors and funds in North America (including &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.renewalpartners.com/&#34;&gt;Renewal Partners&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialcapitalpartners.com/&#34;&gt;Social Capital Partners&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wkkf.org/default.aspx?LanguageID=0&#34;&gt;Kellogg Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rsfsocialfinance.org/&#34;&gt;RSF Social Finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodcap.net/&#34;&gt;Good Capital&lt;/a&gt; and others). To all of you I am tremendously grateful for the generosity of your time, the candor with which you shared your experiences and the enthusiasm with which you&amp;rsquo;ve approached this exploration. Each conversation integrated into my own experiences and readings, and into every other conversation. What has emerged for me is a point of summary from which I feel ready to attempt some active experiments into how do we get better on the frontiers as venturers and venture investors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
