<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lewwwk</title>
    <link>https://lewwwk.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lewwwk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:38:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lewwwk.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coordinating residential energy efficiency, onchain.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/coordinating-residential-energy-efficiency-onchain./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/coordinating-residential-energy-efficiency-onchain./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been close to the challenges of shifting the built environment toward NetZero for a couple of decades now. First in venture capital, then as a founder in the residential thermal energy domain, and since as a board member of Windfall Ecology Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal has always been to simplify and incentivize changes in behaviour and technology adoption. Turns out, massively multiplayer coordination challenges can prove to be incredibly sticky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate X</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/climate-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 15:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/climate-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The impacts of climate change are everywhere, giving rise to new risks and accelerating the need to adapt our physical infrastructure and societies. Regulators are introducing new regulations to disclose those risks to protect the financial system. Investors are adjusting portfolios and adopting new products to accelerate infrastructure adaptation to manage risk and returns. Governments are planning large-scale investments into new infrastructure to prepare for an uncertain future. People are wondering if they are safe and secure where they live and work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two economies, for our future.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/two-economies-for-our-future./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 13:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/two-economies-for-our-future./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
As the twin crises of climate and inequality continue to ripple through society, we have a growing imperative to address them both. If either continues unabated, neither can be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a venture perspective, we are starting to think of the set of solutions that venture can contribute as economies of Transition and Cooperation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Transition Economy&lt;/strong&gt; recognizes the need to accelerate decarbonization and adaptation. It is not about climate or environment, but rather the solutions that allow us to build a future in harmony with both (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://calwave.energy&#34;&gt;CalWave&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://leap.energy&#34;&gt;Leap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wren.co&#34;&gt;Wren&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformative Ventures</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: entry-content
Putting a &amp;lsquo;dent a in the universe&amp;rsquo; is the goal of many mission-driven ventures. Those that succeed will create the new normals for a more vibrant, sustainable, and inclusive future. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt;, we call them transformative ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking and achieving transformative impact is what we are most interested in. It&amp;rsquo;s also different than achieving incremental improvements, regardless of how valuable they might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring more colour to the differences, and what we&amp;rsquo;re most excited about in the years ahead, we&amp;rsquo;re pleased to share our perspective on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation Hotspots</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc/&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt; we are interested in how ventures can create a better future, a future that is more vibrant, prosperous, and sustainable. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;re highlighting a few areas where we see extraordinary opportunity for progress in the next few years as we emerge from the pandemic. While these overlap with existing transition pathways, and will evolve over time, they focus in on certain characteristics of the types of innovations we think have particular momentum and potential for transformative impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world after COVID-19: A framework for considering the future.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-world-after-covid-19-a-framework-for-considering-the-future./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 21:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-world-after-covid-19-a-framework-for-considering-the-future./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image size-large&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR: We already see signs for how our world might change, we just can&amp;rsquo;t be sure which changes will stick. There&amp;rsquo;s a wide range of possible futures ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/shrg6MFWQZRVrBgtF&#34;&gt;collecting a range of perspectives&lt;/a&gt; on the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, to get a sense of what the world might look like after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lucidchart.com/invitations/accept/48331db0-7f52-4230-a362-306b2641bf70&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;m at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-this-so-disruptive&#34; class=&#34;wp-block-heading&#34;&gt;Why is this so disruptive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systemic failures as a result of the pandemic are impacting daily life and order. The speed and severity of these breakdowns is leading to rapid testing of what were previously &amp;lsquo;radical&amp;rsquo; ideas. This creates an opening for meaningfully different futures to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Capabilities, Behaviours, and Systems: How ventures change the world.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/new-capabilities-behaviours-and-systems-how-ventures-change-the-world./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 19:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/new-capabilities-behaviours-and-systems-how-ventures-change-the-world./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A few weeks ago I started sharing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/possibilian/How-we-think-about-ventures-and-the-future-f248f1e4c7d44e15803c24b009648251&#34;&gt;how we think about the transformative potential of ventures&lt;/a&gt;, or in other words, what&amp;rsquo;s the potential for a company to &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to predict if any venture will actually &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo;, we can be sure that if it does, it will have done so through some combination of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introducing meaningful new capabilities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sparking a change in behaviour;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enabling new systems of people, things, and information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Twitter as a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in describing transformative potential in venture.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/an-experiment-in-describing-transformative-potential-in-venture./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 21:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/an-experiment-in-describing-transformative-potential-in-venture./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: {#container role=&amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the bottleneck: The shift from social to systemic impact</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/breaking-the-bottleneck-the-shift-from-social-to-systemic-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 15:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/breaking-the-bottleneck-the-shift-from-social-to-systemic-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/r6iPtc&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Igniter - Systemic Incubation Model&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8682/16468978269_f4ac1315ef_z.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just read &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/trisml&#34;&gt;Tris Lumley&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ssireview.org/blog/entry/transforming_our_anti_social_sector&#34;&gt;Transforming our Anti-Social Sector&lt;/a&gt; along side three posts by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dompotter&#34;&gt;Dom Potter&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/story-social-investment-dom-potter&#34;&gt;The Story of Social Investment&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/accelerating-collaborative-collective-startups-dom-potter&#34;&gt;Rethinking how we support impact driven organizations to start-up&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/collaborative-collective-investment-social-change-dom-potter&#34;&gt;Collaborative and collective impact for social change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, they tell a story of how our best approaches to investing in impact-first ventures are falling short. Incremental improvements to what we are doing are not enough. At the same time, the answer is not in trying to replicate the financial-first startup support ecosystem. Nor is it likely to be &amp;lsquo;something in the middle&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are you doing?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/how-are-you-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/how-are-you-doing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
It&amp;rsquo;s a simple question and it&amp;rsquo;s the heart of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pineHQ.com&#34;&gt;Pine&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s daily check-in. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.com&#34;&gt;we&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;ve been building Pine over the last six weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve answered it about 120 times. This is my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning I&amp;rsquo;d look at the question, not sure where to start. Often I&amp;rsquo;d quickly tap in a few words. Sometimes those words turned into paragraphs. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d check-in with a simple emoticon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, I started noticing things throughout the day. Little thoughts. Sudden reactions. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d reach for Pine and tap them in. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d just pause and watch them play out. And then, it hit me. There was a pattern in my responses, a common theme lurking below the surface that had been shaping my days. Now it&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;ve even done much to change that pattern yet, but simply noticing it lessened its influence and my days are noticeably flowing a little more lightly. Not bad for a simple question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the potential of digital for impact</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reflections-on-the-potential-of-digital-for-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reflections-on-the-potential-of-digital-for-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Digital technologies are increasingly integral to understanding and enabling social innovations. Whether it is as a beneficiary of a social service, a pioneering entrepreneur, or an intermediary, researcher or policy maker, we all increasingly depend on digital technology in our work. As these digital technologies spread to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post7517&#34;&gt;link every person and every thing&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}, we are beginning to see how digital technology is central to our ability to gather data, engage others, and ultimately create the systems of our future. Indeed, it is impossible to think doing so without it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond information: 4 hunches on building the infrastructure for impact</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/beyond-information-4-hunches-on-building-the-infrastructure-for-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 15:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/beyond-information-4-hunches-on-building-the-infrastructure-for-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Eric Henderson of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketsforgood.org&#34;&gt;Markets for Good&lt;/a&gt; recently asked me what was needed to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketsforgood.org/markets-for-good-upgrading-the-infrastructure-for-social-change/&#34;&gt;build an information infrastructure for the social sector&lt;/a&gt;. Their vision is ambitious and important, and with the right approach it could transform how change happens.  Here are my hunches about what&amp;rsquo;s required, and what we&amp;rsquo;re already doing to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Focus on impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get excited about data and information. They&amp;rsquo;re hot topics, and rightly so. As we wade into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post7513&#34;&gt;digital revolution&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;re flooded with things demanding our attention. And the things we want others to see keep getting lost in the tsunami of everything else. But let&amp;rsquo;s step back for a second.  Think of this like swimming across a river. The goal is to get across the river, not to go for a swim. What I need is a way to get across. And in the case of this infrastructure, what we need goes beyond data standards, quality, and accessibility to include supports that help us achieve impact more efficiently, and with greater efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developers seeking adventure.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/developers-seeking-adventure./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 13:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/developers-seeking-adventure./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
We&amp;rsquo;re looking for the next adventure at &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.com&#34;&gt;Igniter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a small team of developers, facilitators and entrepreneurs. We build web applications that invite connection, nurture relationship, and build understanding. Our approach is friendly and designed to facilitate flow. We start simply, work quickly and care about what we&amp;rsquo;re crafting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our short time together, we&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to quietly craft some great solutions with some ambitious partners:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yourquestions.mcdonalds.ca&#34;&gt;Our Food. Your Questions.&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://tribalddb.com&#34;&gt;Tribal DDB&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcdonalds.ca&#34;&gt;McDonald&amp;rsquo;s Canada&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://waittimes.cihi.ca&#34;&gt;Wait Times. For Priority Procedures in Canada.&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://normativedesign.com&#34;&gt;Normative Design&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cihi.ca&#34;&gt;Candian Institute for Health Information&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love working with creative agencies and organizations that are shaping the future. If that sounds like you, we&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clog with me! The future of websites.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/clog-with-me-the-future-of-websites./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 15:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/clog-with-me-the-future-of-websites./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Last fall when I revived &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.com&#34;&gt;Igniter&lt;/a&gt; I did the standard setup of website, &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniterhq.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;tumblog&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/igniterhq&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; account all of which have remained mostly untouched.  They didn&amp;rsquo;t feel right at the time, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usv.com/2012/06/internet-presence-usv.php&#34;&gt;this post about the future of USV.com&lt;/a&gt; that it clicked. We didn&amp;rsquo;t need a website or a blog, we needed a &amp;ldquo;clog&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clog |kläg, klôg| noun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;1 a shoe with a thick wooden sole.&lt;/del&gt; &amp;lt;- &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.ca/search?q=clog+images&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;prmd=imvns&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;tbo=u&amp;amp;source=univ&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=8LHpT-OxKISv6gHXroH-DA&amp;amp;ved=0CFYQsAQ&amp;amp;biw=1214&amp;amp;bih=670&#34;&gt;all sorts of awesome&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of civilization and social innovation</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-evolution-of-civilization-and-social-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 06:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-evolution-of-civilization-and-social-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Humanity is in a chaotic phase, evolving from a civilization born of the industrial revolution to a civilization emerging from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/thoughts/the-revolution-is-digital/&#34; title=&#34;The revolution is digital&#34;&gt;digital revolution&lt;/a&gt;. As the pace of this evolution increases, so does our effort to direct it. That effort is called social innovation and it too is evolving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From revolutions in music and media to the uprisings of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arab_Spring&#34;&gt;Arab Spring&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement&#34;&gt;Occupy movement&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WikiLeaks&#34;&gt;Wikileaks&lt;/a&gt;, we can see a common pattern. Each is enabled by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_electronics&#34; title=&#34;Digital electronics&#34;&gt;digital technology&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} and the result of a complex social process comprised of many individual actions. Often they are user-driven, unfold rapidly, and challenge or circumvent a system that no-longer works they way its participants want.  Ultimately, this is about people and the way they want the future to work, for them. It is the evolution of our civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The nature of digital technology</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-nature-of-digital-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 03:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-nature-of-digital-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Digital technology is not about circuits and wires, it is about data and connectivity. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1416544054/&#34;&gt;the Nature of Technology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W._Brian_Arthur&#34;&gt;W. Brain Arthur&lt;/a&gt; explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Digitization allows functionalities to be combined even if they come from different domains, because once they enter the digital domain they become objects of the same type &amp;ndash; data strings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data also has another property. It is intangible. Where physical materials are limited by scarcity, data thrives in abundance, able to replicate freely without diminishing the original.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The revolution is digital</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-revolution-is-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 03:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-revolution-is-digital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Industrial_Revolution&#34; title=&#34;Industrial Revolution&#34;&gt;The industrial revolution&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} began with technology that allowed us to manipulate our world in an entirely new way. As it developed it began to shape how we organize ourselves and even what we thought.  Over time it shaped civilization as we know it. And now, as we reach the limits of that civilization it appears history is about to repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his 2001 book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Macroshift-Navigating-Transformation-Sustainable-World/dp/1576751635&#34;&gt;Macroshift&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34; title=&#34;Ervin László&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} observed that new civilizations begin with &amp;ldquo;technological innovations that destabilize the established structures and institutions of society.&amp;rdquo; In the last decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_electronics&#34; title=&#34;Digital electronics&#34;&gt;digital technology&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} enable revolutions and uprisings around the world and trigger exisistential crises in the industries of music and media. Indeed, there is virtually nothing that digital technology has yet to impact. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/W._Brian_Arthur&#34; title=&#34;W. Brian Arthur&#34;&gt;W. Brian Arthur&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} describes in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Nature-Technology-What-How-Evolves/dp/1416544054%3FSubscriptionId%3D0G81C5DAZ03ZR9WH9X82%26tag%3Dzemanta-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1416544054&#34; title=&#34;The Nature of Technology: What It Is and How It Evolves&#34;&gt;The Nature of Technology&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;amazon noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorry about the hangover</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/sorry-about-the-hangover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 21:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/sorry-about-the-hangover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: mceTemp
Hey there,
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry about the hangover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great party.  Never thought it would end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left a couple bucks on the table. Hope that covers the booze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I think the freezer thawed and someone puked in the well.  Might want to double-check before you cook up those last burgers or take a drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also noticed there seems to be something wrong with the air conditioner. Think some of us were using it as an ashtray last night and it started making some weird sounds. Anyway, might want to take a look at that too. Heard it&amp;rsquo;s going to get hot today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Irrationality required. No substitutions.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/irrationality-required.-no-substitutions./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 18:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/irrationality-required.-no-substitutions./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nimrodcooper/492473612/&#34; title=&#34;Clash of the Titans 01 by nimrodcooper, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Clash of the Titans 01&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/215/492473612_b960dc5124.jpg&#34;&gt;{.alignright decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;176&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;121&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art and engineering. Intuition and intelligence. Heart and mind. It&amp;rsquo;s at the intersections that our future manifests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately in entrepreneurship, design, and social innovation there&amp;rsquo;s a definite leaning toward the rational side of this balance. A big part of that is the availability of measurable data. Because if we can measure, we can test. We can optimize. We can iterate. We can improve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanity is conversation.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/humanity-is-conversation./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 14:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/humanity-is-conversation./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/lecercle/481267425/&#34; title=&#34;Calcutta Coffee House -  5 by lecercle, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Calcutta Coffee House - 5&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/218/481267425_153625e09f.jpg&#34;&gt;{.alignright decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;144&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;216&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cluetrain.com/book/markets.html&#34;&gt;Markets are conversations&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;rdquo;}&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailymile.com/people/Igniter/entries/9078704&#34;&gt;a long run yesterday&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} along the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thames_River_(Ontario)&#34;&gt;Thames&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} (yes we have one &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London,_Ontario&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} too) I got thinking about the Cluetrain and that core thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, and&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Humanity is conversation&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversation is a human thing. We can&amp;rsquo;t help but have it, with others, and with ourselves. Whether we have it or not it keeps happening all around us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Activity is Your Currency</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/your-activity-is-your-currency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 15:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/your-activity-is-your-currency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 1em; display: block;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 151px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Claudius_II_coin_%28colourised%29.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3b/Claudius_II_coin_%28colourised%29.png&#34; title=&#34;Standard Catalog of World Coins&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;151&#34; height=&#34;147&#34; alt=&#34;Standard Catalog of World Coins&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image via Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://epic.io&#34;&gt;Epic&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re introducing Epicredits as a currency to help you reward and accomplish what matters to you. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://makeitepic.com/r/av9iWUHOTP%20&#34;&gt;signup now&lt;/a&gt; to start collecting and get notified when it&amp;rsquo;s live later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who want to learn more, read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://epic.io&#34;&gt;Epic&lt;/a&gt; is based on the realization that more and more of what we do produces a signal in the cloud. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a tweet, a document update, a blog post or a bookmark there&amp;rsquo;s a record of it somewhere. In fact, when someone is trying to get your attention, even if it&amp;rsquo;s a simple as clicking a link, it&amp;rsquo;s a share of your activity that they want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summit on the Future</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/summit-on-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 06:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/summit-on-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/5502283115/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1599 by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG_1599&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5019/5502283115_081881c1da.jpg&#34;&gt;{.aligncenter decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;233&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;350&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6907&#34;&gt;future of organization&lt;/a&gt; has arrived. Like with sustainable coffee, cleantech, and the social trifecta (entrepreneurship/finance/innovation) before,  I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the shift in conversation from &amp;ldquo;no that will never happen/it must be stopped at all costs&amp;rdquo; to, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s happening or inevitable/how can I play&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s the shift from an avoidable future to an inevitable reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically for me, this is a time to shift fully from thinking to doing. And yet, I know it is the time when the opportunity for understanding really begins. So, as I sit here in the wee hours of the morning wondering why I am writing this post, I realize that I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for someone to hold the space for this thinking to shift to the next level to. While I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly what that is, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nurture.biz/about/jean-russell/&#34;&gt;Jean Russell&lt;/a&gt; seems to capture the direction in &lt;a href=&#34;http://thrivable.net/2011/05/integration/&#34;&gt;her post on integration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epic.io in Context</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/epic.io-in-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 16:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/epic.io-in-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/5502286555/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1618 by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5218/5502286555_dfecb9557b.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Into the mirage&#34;&gt;{.aligncenter decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;233&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;350&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://epic.io&#34;&gt;Epic.io&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} is the latest in a series of &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/igniter/bfsResearch&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} and &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com/igniter/bfsExperiments&#34;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} at inspiring a better future sooner. It is designed as a product at the intersection between the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6800&#34;&gt;evolutionary change&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} in &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6907&#34;&gt;how we, as humans, come together&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} and the pains of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post7436&#34;&gt;collaboration overload&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} we experience from that change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root discoveries of this journey over the last 4 years boil down to the fact that purpose is what motivates us to step up to something greater, and progress is what fuels us to keep going. There are no two more powerful ingredients in making great things happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration Overload</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/collaboration-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 14:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/collaboration-overload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/5502836760/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_1447 by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG_1447&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5176/5502836760_d91e9114ea.jpg&#34;&gt;{.aligncenter decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;233&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;350&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the mobile, social web is wonderful. More than that, it is providing a foundational base for an &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6800&#34;&gt;evolution in civilization&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}. While the long-run potential of that is great, there are a lot of transitional tremors along the way. Those tremors are shaking nations, industries, and even our lives. On the personal level, I&amp;rsquo;m calling that tremor collaboration overload.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You are a…</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/you-are-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 14:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/you-are-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I recently tweeted the question: &amp;ldquo;What term to you prefer. &amp;lsquo;user&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;person&amp;rsquo;, something else.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received some pretty polarized responses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m torn myself. Not entirely comfortable with &amp;lsquo;user&amp;rsquo; but I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across any options I like better. &amp;lsquo;Participant&amp;rsquo; is interesting, but somehow still undervaluing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Any better suggestions or examples?
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making it Epic (alpha edition)</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/making-it-epic-alpha-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 16:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/making-it-epic-alpha-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/square-id-v1-rgk2iu.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/square-id-v1-rgk2iu.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re not embarrassed when you ship your first version you waited too long.&amp;rdquo; ~ &lt;a href=&#34;http://ma.tt/2010/11/one-point-oh/&#34;&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday evening, &lt;a href=&#34;http://walkah.net&#34;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/thinksmith&#34;&gt;Alan&lt;/a&gt;, and I linked arms, cringed a bit, and hit send. The first batch of invites to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://epic.io&#34;&gt;Epic.io&lt;/a&gt; private alpha were out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already we&amp;rsquo;re learning a lot. As &amp;rsquo;embarrassing&amp;rsquo; as some of the things we see are, what we&amp;rsquo;re gaining from real-world usage is worth it. Feedback has been real and is helping us prioritize what needs attention most.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More pirate!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/more-pirate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/more-pirate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/More-Pirate-ez2svt.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/More-Pirate-ez2svt.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Downloading-Sneakers-Reinvented-Capitalism-Innovation/dp/1416532188&#34;&gt;The Pirate&amp;rsquo;s Dilemma&lt;/a&gt; thanks to a chance encounter with the most excellent pirate &lt;a href=&#34;http://thepiratesdilemma.com/&#34; title=&#34;Matt Mason&#34;&gt;Matt Mason&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} himself got me thinking. What jumped out was a rawness &amp;ndash; not in an aggressive way &amp;ndash; but in natural, passionate sense. It&amp;rsquo;s the very rawness that we try and institutionalize out of our society. The very rawness that actually creates the conditions for our greatest leaps&amp;hellip; leapfrogging incrementalism&amp;hellip; right into a different future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RealVote – my simple promise to democracy</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/realvote-my-simple-promise-to-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 18:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/realvote-my-simple-promise-to-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Another election has come and gone and while voter turnout increased, the substance of the debate hit new lows. So, while my passion is at its peak, here&amp;rsquo;s my simple commitment to revive real democracy in my community for the next election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will create a platform for people in my district to ask questions, and invite all candidates for that district to respond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will campaign door to door to make people aware, gather questions, and share the answers for what&amp;rsquo;s been answered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next election in my area is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.electionalmanac.com/canada/ontario/&#34;&gt;October 6, 2011 (Ontario)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My district is &lt;a href=&#34;http://fyed.elections.on.ca/fyed/en/map_page_en.jsp?dcode=045&#34;&gt;London West&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the best way I can think to fight partisanship in favour of real dialogue and engagement. We all deserve more. It&amp;rsquo;s time I took responsibility. It&amp;rsquo;s time I did something to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People, purpose, and a better future, sooner.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/people-purpose-and-a-better-future-sooner./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 21:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/people-purpose-and-a-better-future-sooner./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The shifts underway at &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6800&#34;&gt;civilizational&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6907&#34;&gt;organizational&lt;/a&gt; levels are of course happening at the personal level too. That shift, which was touched on in each of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Power-Pull-Smartly-Things-Motion/dp/0465019358/&#34;&gt;Power of Pull&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Future-Management-Gary-Hamel/dp/1422102505/&#34;&gt;Future of Management&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Enterprise-Classic-Beer/dp/0471948373/&#34;&gt;Heart of Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6907&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;), is best brought forth in &lt;a href=&#34;http://danpink.com&#34;&gt;Dan Pink&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s latest book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danpink.com/drive&#34;&gt;Drive&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the book or seen either of his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation.html&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt; or RSA Animation (see below), it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular quotes captures it well:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new threads of ‘Organization’</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-new-threads-of-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 17:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-new-threads-of-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 160px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/4671661985/&#34; title=&#34;A thread runs through it -  by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4019/4671661985_b6ec18aece_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;A thread runs through it.&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;Thread&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;A thread runs through it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization is one of our most potent social technologies. In a world where chaos, connectivity, and creativity have risen to new heights, increased attention on the topic is both natural and welcomed. Quite simply, if &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post6800&#34;&gt;our civilization is set to pivot&lt;/a&gt;, getting better at it will help us realize a better future, sooner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our civilization is set to pivot.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/our-civilization-is-set-to-pivot./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 18:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/our-civilization-is-set-to-pivot./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/4692003012/&#34; title=&#34;Rorsharch by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1283/4692003012_36f92dfe56.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Rorschach&#34;&gt;{.aligncenter decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;240&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;320&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s any need to replay the state of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear we&amp;rsquo;re in a period of intense change, where the many systems of our society have reached their limits, where our civilization is set to pivot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2001, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34; title=&#34;Ervin László&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} wrote about this in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Macroshift-Navigating-Transformation-Sustainable-World/dp/1576751635&#34;&gt;Macroshift&lt;/a&gt;. He found a common pattern in civilizations over the course of our history. They set out on a trajectory based on certain combination of technology and mindset. At some point, that trajectory becomes unsustainable and the civilizations reach, like any system, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bifurcation_theory&#34; title=&#34;Bifurcation theory&#34;&gt;bifurcation point&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;}. Either they breakthrough based on a new combo of technology and mindset or they breakdown. While breakdown is alarming, it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty common in the history of civilization. The only problem is, this is the first time our civilization has been global. Breakdown would really, really suck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in systemic entrepreneurship. The time is now.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/lessons-in-systemic-entrepreneurship.-the-time-is-now./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 14:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/lessons-in-systemic-entrepreneurship.-the-time-is-now./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Late last fall I had the opportunity to conduct an intensive &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcconnellfoundation.ca/en/resources/report/vartana-review-a-reflection-on-the-history-lessons-and-legacy-of&#34;&gt;review of the Vartana initiative&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcconnellfoundation.ca/en&#34;&gt;J.W. McConnell Family Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vartana.org&#34;&gt;Vartana&lt;/a&gt; was an initiative to create a chartable bank in Canada dedicated to serving the voluntary sector. It held the promise of changing the availability of capital for the sector and as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banking_in_Canada#Regulation&#34;&gt;Schedule I chartered bank&lt;/a&gt;, influencing the Canadian financial services industry. While ultimately felled by the financial services collapse of 2008, it holds some valuable lessons in entrepreneurial pursuit of systemic change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time to bring the passion back.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/its-time-to-bring-the-passion-back./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 14:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/its-time-to-bring-the-passion-back./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://patpitingolo.blogspot.com/2009/02/special-request.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_M-6E-8Ol4Y4/SaXr6LFD1MI/AAAAAAAAAQY/r6x8U9dHNJk/s400/mead+quote+web.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://patpitingolo.blogspot.com/2009/02/special-request.html&#34;&gt;lost and found: A Special Request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot lately on how this happens. As an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entrepreneur&#34; title=&#34;Entrepreneur&#34;&gt;entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} interested in a better future, sooner there are endless examples to point to. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grameen-info.org/&#34; title=&#34;Grameen Bank&#34;&gt;Grameen Bank&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, &lt;a href=&#34;http://benjerry.com&#34;&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://stonyfield.com&#34;&gt;Stonyfield Farms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kernel.org/&#34; title=&#34;Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet&#34; title=&#34;Internet&#34;&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;}, the Web, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikipedia.org&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.craigslist.org/&#34; title=&#34;Craigslist&#34;&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} are all ones that come to mind for different reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that seems universal in all these is passion, that unmistakable blend of purpose and persistence that drives things forward.  It&amp;rsquo;s what brings that small group together to get something done, when no one really knows yet what they are doing or how it will happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unfollow fun.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/unfollow-fun./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 02:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/unfollow-fun./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I was outed today with a healthy dose of snark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/Outed-thipzp.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/Outed-thipzp.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This was not a case of &amp;ldquo;oh, sorry, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} must have somehow unfollowed you&amp;rdquo;, it was a case of &amp;ldquo;ya, I unfollowed you&amp;hellip; and everyone else.&amp;rdquo; You see, I&amp;rsquo;ve long valued Twitter a brilliant discovery tool &amp;ndash; both for information and new relationships. Reading Power of Pull recently reminded me of that which got me to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/thinking-msxtba.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/thinking-msxtba.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this morning while waiting for a meeting I happened across a tweet that led me to a post which mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://manageflitter.com&#34;&gt;ManageFlitter&lt;/a&gt; (oh Twitter how you do that to me). I&amp;rsquo;ve tweaked my follow list a few times there before but this time when I got there, I decided to start entirely from scratch. Not because I&amp;rsquo;m bored with who I was following, but because I want to reset the power of Twitter to pull me in new directions. With a new venture underway it felt like the perfect time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fear is Death</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/fear-is-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 16:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/fear-is-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I happened across &lt;a href=&#34;http://alexbogusky.posterous.com/&#34;&gt;Alex Bogusky&amp;rsquo;s posterous&lt;/a&gt; yesterday and his sub-line stuck with me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear is the mortal enemy of creativity, innovation and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it prattled around in my head during my run this morning it struck me that fear is death. It&amp;rsquo;s an insatiable beast that tries to consume everything it encounters. It sucks energy out of us and pulls us back from progress. It makes us cower. In big ways and little ways. And each time we do a little bit of us or our relationships die.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups are Easy – a haiku</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/startups-are-easy-a-haiku/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 15:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/startups-are-easy-a-haiku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
startups are easy&lt;br&gt;
but sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t work well&lt;br&gt;
kinda like WebVan
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in system failure, design, and purpose.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/lessons-in-system-failure-design-and-purpose./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 07:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/lessons-in-system-failure-design-and-purpose./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
My &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post4060&#34;&gt;recent adventures&lt;/a&gt; with my local utility offered up some great lessons on system failure, design, and purpose. I&amp;rsquo;ve jotted them down here as hunches to look back on rather than a epiphany of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Systemic failures can and will happen. They will happen often and their occurrence is an excellent opportunity to better understand your systems and the things that system is interacting with. Elimination of failure is impossible and probably unhealthy. Not learning from it is irresponsible and undoubtedly inefficient. Also, failure is subjective. What might look like massive failure to one participant in the system maybe be inconsequential to the rest of the system and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UnionGas – regulated utility shuts off service WITHOUT NOTICE.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/uniongas-regulated-utility-shuts-off-service-without-notice./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 16:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/uniongas-regulated-utility-shuts-off-service-without-notice./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
This a story of how UnionGas disconnected my natural gas service WITHOUT NOTICE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning we received a notice on our front door that our gas had been disconnected. We were home at the time but the gas guy just hung the notice on the door AFTER turning the gas off. Stunned, I called UnionGas. They told me that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t paid in 6 months. Stunned again, I looked into my payment history and sure enough I hadn&amp;rsquo;t paid. I thought I was paying, and had absolutely no reason to believe I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been paying because, well, they GAVE ME NO NOTICE. Simple solution, pay up? Nope. Now that the gas has been disconnected, I will be without an essential utility for a minimum of 5 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unexpected is always the highlight.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-unexpected-is-always-the-highlight./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 16:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-unexpected-is-always-the-highlight./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I recently attended the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skollworldforum.com&#34; title=&#34;Skoll World Forum&#34;&gt;Skoll World Forum&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} on Social Entrepreneurship. Going in I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of an agenda but did end up with an experience that was worthwhile and possibly pivotal. The reason of course, as with all events it seems, is the people that gathered and connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable: Pamela Hartigan and Jeff Skoll at Opening Plenary --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the content and conversation perspective, the highlight for me was the focus on systems as core to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_entrepreneurship&#34; title=&#34;Social entrepreneurship&#34;&gt;social entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;}. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roger_Martin&#34; title=&#34;Roger Martin&#34;&gt;Roger Martin&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} tagged disrupting and establishing equilibria as the ultimate purpose, and previously tired conversations around metrics became flavoured with the emergent dynamics of working at the level of systems. While applying rigour to scale and diffuse innovation was a hot topic, people also recognized that the most innovative work often reflects insanity before it becomes recognized as brilliance. That this conversation was happening here was a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunches on the evolution of scholarly publishing</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/hunches-on-the-evolution-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 18:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/hunches-on-the-evolution-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
As part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://changemedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring ways to surface and accelerate research related to this emerging system of social technologies. The idea of creating a journal on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-medium-of-change-context&#34;&gt;the medium of change&lt;/a&gt; came up in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post500&#34;&gt;October event&lt;/a&gt;. What follows are some hunches about the evolution of academic publishing arising from that work. If you are involved or interested in this field, I&amp;rsquo;d love to get your reactions and perspectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background on research and academic publication.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonfire of Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/bonfire-of-beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 15:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/bonfire-of-beliefs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I know a few people have been wondering about what going on silent retreat was like. To give it some flavour I decided to share my experience. But first, fair warning. If you are someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like &amp;lsquo;fluffy stuff&amp;rsquo; you may not want to keep reading&amp;hellip; but then again you may also then miss what I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be the most purely practical thing possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my youth I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in existential questions like is this world just a dream? And if it&amp;rsquo;s a dream, is it my dream that everyone is a part of or am I part of someone else&amp;rsquo;s dream along with everything else? Over the years I had fun conversations with my friends, dipped into things like physics, philosophy, raiki, and buddhism but nothing seemed to stick. Then early in 2007 I was staying with a good friend and we got into this favourite conversation of mine with him and his partner. Over the next two evenings his partner asked me some deeply simple questions and shared some recordings from &lt;a href=&#34;http://adyashanti.org&#34;&gt;Adyashanti&lt;/a&gt; and a book by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spiritualteachers.org/jed_mckenna.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jed McKenna&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. On my way home that next night I was reading the book when right in between two words something in me awoke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Innovation @ Ivey</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-innovation-@-ivey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 13:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-innovation-@-ivey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::: entry-content
Quick post to share today&amp;rsquo;s presentations for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ivey.uwo.ca/centres/building/outreach/&#34;&gt;Social Innovation @ Ivey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First is my opening intro, which pulls from a core theme but adds a little more about my history and the levels, forms, and tools of social entrepreneurship  &amp;ndash; or my best simplification of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::: {#__ss_3528660 style=&amp;ldquo;width: 425px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/were-screwed&#34; title=&#34;we&#39;re screwed&#34;&gt;we&amp;rsquo;re screwed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;padding: 5px 0 12px;&amp;rdquo;}
View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt;.
:::
::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second, is a for a last minute stand-in role on the social finance workshop.  Thankfully the wise and gracious &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialcapitalpartners.com/about-us/team#karim&#34;&gt;Karim Harji&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialfinance.ca&#34;&gt;SocialFinance.ca&lt;/a&gt; shared this great, detailed deck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiring students. What would you tell them?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/inspiring-students.-what-would-you-tell-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 15:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/inspiring-students.-what-would-you-tell-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m scheduled to open the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ivey.uwo.ca/centres/building/outreach/&#34;&gt;Social Innovation @ Ivey Form&lt;/a&gt; and have been asked to get the audience of students &amp;lsquo;fired up&amp;rsquo; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_entrepreneurship&#34; title=&#34;Social entrepreneurship&#34;&gt;social entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} and innovation. What would you tell them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are currently deciding on which electives to take and of course what career path to take &amp;ndash; a big part of why I love doing these talks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to tell my story, touch on social entrepreneurship and social finance and have 30 minutes to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring a RoR developer!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/hiring-a-ror-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/hiring-a-ror-developer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m eager to get building and am hiring a developer. Think you might know anyone &amp;ndash; please help spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the posting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a team of social and tech sector entrepreneurs.&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re launching a startup that builds apps for a better future, sooner.&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a full-time Ruby on Rails developer with the chops to help make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What our RoR developer will do.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; work with us to build solid, scalable apps, that people love using,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; code brilliantly producing code that&amp;rsquo;s clean, elegant, and efficient,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; figure it out and get it done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Right? Bullshit.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/right-bullshit./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 02:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/right-bullshit./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Pardon the profanity, but I&amp;rsquo;m tired of the bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People like to be right. Often being right means making other people wrong. This is not productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying that it is productive because you are engaging in debate&amp;hellip; does not make it productive either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you are really doing is trying to win to be right. And who does that help? You. Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t it help? Everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be productive, contribute. Instead of being right, help the recipient of your righteousness try and explore their issue further. And if you find you&amp;rsquo;re not learning through the conversation then, again, stop trying to be right. If you can&amp;rsquo;t do that, shut up and do something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stand up for Mothering!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/stand-up-for-mothering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 22:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/stand-up-for-mothering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
If mothering isn&amp;rsquo;t one of the more important things that shape our society and our future, I don&amp;rsquo;t know what is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow though I think it gets taken for granted. That couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more clear from the announcement that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yorku.ca/arm/&#34;&gt;the leading organization that researches the topic&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yorku.ca/arm/ARMLetter.pdf&#34;&gt;being forced to close&lt;/a&gt;. How is it that an organization like this cannot get more support?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, people are making themselves heard on the interwebz. My partner &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/doulamama&#34;&gt;Shawna&lt;/a&gt; started up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=338745346265&#34;&gt;Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt; and the blogosphere and media are taking notice too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On privilege and change.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/on-privilege-and-change./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 20:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/on-privilege-and-change./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I am privileged. Very privileged, and too often I lose sight of that and what it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a healthy and able mid-thirties, white, upper-class, educated male, I am in a position where I don&amp;rsquo;t face discrimination in any way. I can go for a run in the park at night, breeze through airport security, meet someone for the first time and have the luxury of going about life undisturbed. And this is of course because everything I use and interact with is desinged with me in mind, usually by people very much like me. Physical things like chairs, cars, devices like my blackberry. Virtual things like websites, apps, content. Structural things like laws, regulations, customs and norms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into 2010</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/into-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 16:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/into-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Last year was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pivot&#34;&gt;pivot&lt;/a&gt; for me. But while I&amp;rsquo;m entering with a new stance, my direction, my intention, remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/4099337665/&#34; title=&#34;Taking the high road. by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Taking the high road.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2447/4099337665_a2306d9bfc.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Taking the high road.&#34;&gt;{.alignnone decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;333&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryancoleman.ca/&#34;&gt;Ryan Coleman&lt;/a&gt; and I crafted this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have fun, live well, and make the world better by facilitating ambitious ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post412&#34;&gt;Like last year&lt;/a&gt;, my focus rests on social technologies and how they are shifting our culture, disrupting and enabling the systems of our society, and changing the way in which we came together. &lt;a href=&#34;http://changemedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; is the charitable expression of that, Shouldless is the commercial expression, and ProjectX is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/tags/projectx/&#34;&gt;ongoing work&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; re-inspired by the Vartana review &amp;ndash; to develop tools and approaches to building those things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2009 in review</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/my-2009-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 15:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/my-2009-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I was just writing an update to some great partners of mine and realized I needed to include a recap of 2009 for some context on what&amp;rsquo;s next. That of course reminded me that I&amp;rsquo;d yet to post one. So here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34; style=&#34;width: 233px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/4096825949/&#34; title=&#34;Into the wild. by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2561/4096825949_c625900066.jpg&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; fetchpriority=&#34;high&#34; width=&#34;233&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; alt=&#34;Into the wild.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2009 was a pivotal one for me &amp;ndash; a year of transition. It was full of new adventures and an unexpected closure of &lt;a href=&#34;http://cleanenergydevelopments.com/&#34;&gt;an old one&lt;/a&gt;. 2009 started with a bunch of excitement and energy around the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-social-venture-commons-1130928&#34;&gt;Social Venture Commons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post371&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post406&#34;&gt;Thread.io&lt;/a&gt;. A group of us had come together and were sweating out an experiment in peer-producing some apps that we thought could help people come together and build a better world by using &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post355&#34;&gt;public micro-messaging&lt;/a&gt;. We had some encouraging feedback on the concepts but we missed the mark and didn&amp;rsquo;t get enough traction (users or funding). We had felt we were constantly 2 weeks ahead of &amp;rsquo;everyone else&amp;rsquo; and when we took stock of what we felt we&amp;rsquo;d need to get to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;viable venture&lt;/a&gt;, we just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it with what we had. I had failed at guiding us through to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product&#34;&gt;viable product&lt;/a&gt; and estimating what it would take to get us there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPad is sneaky.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-ipad-is-sneaky./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 02:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-ipad-is-sneaky./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
It seems that every day I find myself wanting an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ipad/&#34;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; for something. Those moments are coming not from being on the computer, but from going about my daily life, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I think is what the iPad is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out thinking it would be ideal for my kids to use their favourite learning sites and with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ipad/specs/&#34;&gt;the attached keyboard&lt;/a&gt; as my mom&amp;rsquo;s next computer for the basic email and browsing that she really needs it for. But I&amp;rsquo;m also now finding a bunch of other uses, like browsing for movies to rent, watching those movies while travelling, reviewing our finances on &lt;a href=&#34;http://wesabe.com&#34; title=&#34;Wesabe&#34;&gt;Wesabe&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, etc. Shawna also mentioned using it for recipes while cooking and I could see using it for logging &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailymile.com&#34; title=&#34;dailymile&#34;&gt;DailyMile&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} runs as I stretch. I could even see it being the new tool for in-meeting presentations and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.omnigroup.com/2010/01/29/ipad-or-bust/&#34;&gt;napkin sketches&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Entrepreneurship? What are you waiting for?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-entrepreneurship-what-are-you-waiting-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 22:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-entrepreneurship-what-are-you-waiting-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m presenting the deck below at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uoguelph.ca/~envsymp/&#34;&gt;16th Annual Environmental Sciences Symposium&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uoguelph.ca/&#34; title=&#34;University of Guelph&#34;&gt;University of Guelph&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}. I&amp;rsquo;m told to expect an audience of about 200 &amp;ndash; mostly undergrads. That&amp;rsquo;s one of my favourite scenarios. Talking about any form of entrepreneurship to people about to embark on the rest of their lives is fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the devastation in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haiti&#34; title=&#34;Haiti&#34;&gt;Haiti&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} right now though, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try something different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMicroBlogging amps up the medium of change.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/openmicroblogging-amps-up-the-medium-of-change./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 16:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/openmicroblogging-amps-up-the-medium-of-change./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4043/4246063782_5ee2e9a364.jpg&#34;&gt;{.alignleft decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;245&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;163&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 18th was the first ever &lt;a href=&#34;http://statuscamp.org&#34;&gt;StatusCamp&lt;/a&gt;. It was also another &lt;a href=&#34;http://ChangeMedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; experiment &amp;ndash; bringing the context of the medium of change to the developers building its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was an excellent day with over two dozen folks including the &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.net/&#34; title=&#34;status.net&#34;&gt;Status.net&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} team and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/peterdeitz&#34;&gt;Peter Deitz&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialactions.com/&#34; title=&#34;Social Actions&#34;&gt;SocialActions&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}. It was an amazing event to learn about where Status.net and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openmicroblogging.org/&#34; title=&#34;OpenMicroBlogging&#34;&gt;OpenMicroBlogging&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} initiative (OMB) are going.  The wiki has &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.net/wiki/OpenMicroblogging_and_Federation&#34;&gt;more details on OMB&lt;/a&gt; but it is due for a major new release and will be integrating &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pubsubhubbub/&#34;&gt;PubSubHubBub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://activitystrea.ms&#34;&gt;ActivityStrea.ms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salmon-protocol.org/&#34;&gt;Salmon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/webfinger/&#34; title=&#34;WebFinger&#34;&gt;WebFinger&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}.  What this means is an integration of emerging protocols to put people at the centre of micro-messaging. Not only is this a positive protocol development, but it signals the collaboration of major participants in this field to create an 0pen, interoperable system &amp;ndash; an essential aspect of the medium of change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChangeMedium</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/changemedium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 19:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/changemedium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://changemedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; is coming to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montreal&#34; title=&#34;Montreal&#34;&gt;Montreal&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} on December 18th. Following up on his participation at &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post500&#34;&gt;#cmToronto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://status.net&#34;&gt;Status.net&lt;/a&gt; founder &lt;a href=&#34;http://identi.ca/evan&#34; title=&#34;Evan Prodromou&#34;&gt;Evan Prodromou&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} has invited us to join them at their first ever &lt;a href=&#34;http://statuscamp.org&#34;&gt;StatusCamp&lt;/a&gt;. Status.net is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source&#34; title=&#34;Open source&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} micro-messaging platform that can be hosted independently as a private or public platform like &lt;a href=&#34;http://laconi.ca&#34; title=&#34;Laconica&#34;&gt;laconi.ca&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}. For us at ChangeMedium public micro-messaing is at the heart of this inflection in the web and at the core of the medium for change. That perspective is what hope to bring to StatusCamp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lemonade Stand 2010</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/lemonade-stand-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 15:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/lemonade-stand-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Lemonade stands are an old symbol of enterprising youth &amp;ndash; where the best ones were the ones that made the most money. Today&amp;rsquo;s kids are still enterprising but they&amp;rsquo;re doing for a different reason &amp;ndash; to help others out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently seen it first hand as I was recruited by my munchkins to create a calendar of drawings from them and their friends together in support of &lt;a href=&#34;http://kidssavingtherainforest.org&#34;&gt;Kids Saving the Rainforest&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see how quickly the kids came together to make this happen. They&amp;rsquo;re learning that joy of coming together and creating something for a greater purpose. They&amp;rsquo;re learning how to get others to help out. They&amp;rsquo;re simply excited to be &amp;lsquo;helping&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChangeMedium – advancing the medium of change.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/changemedium-advancing-the-medium-of-change./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 01:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/changemedium-advancing-the-medium-of-change./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit remiss in not posting this sooner. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryancoleman&#34;&gt;@ryancoleman&lt;/a&gt; for pulling this overview together. You can of course learn more over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://changemedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; and keep updated by joining the &lt;a href=&#34;http://group.changemedium.org&#34;&gt;group&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the progress we&amp;rsquo;re making and looking forward to sharing more and welcoming others into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::: {#__ss_2453796 style=&amp;ldquo;width:425px;text-align:left&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/rycoleman/changemedium-overview&#34; title=&#34;ChangeMedium: Overview&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium: Overview&lt;/a&gt;{style=&amp;ldquo;font:14px Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif;display:block;margin:12px 0 3px 0;text-decoration:underline;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;font-size:11px;font-family:tahoma,arial;height:26px;padding-top:2px;&amp;rdquo;}
View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt;{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration:underline;&amp;rdquo;} from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/rycoleman&#34;&gt;Ryan Coleman Design &amp;amp; Consulting | Freelance Information Designer &amp;amp; Facilitator&lt;/a&gt;{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration:underline;&amp;rdquo;}.
:::
::::
:::::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#cmToronto Recap</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/%23cmtoronto-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 22:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/%23cmtoronto-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 163px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/sets/72157622542758987/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3230/4046265077_5b6f81ed32.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Presentations @ #cmToronto&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;163&#34; height=&#34;245&#34; alt=&#34;Engaged...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Engaged...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23cmToronto&#34;&gt;#cmToronto&lt;/a&gt; opened on a gray Saturday morning with an introduction to &lt;a href=&#34;http://changemedium.org&#34;&gt;ChangeMedium&lt;/a&gt; and the day by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/igniter&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/walkah&#34;&gt;James Walker&lt;/a&gt; followed up with an overview of what to expect during the hack session.  The orientation reminded participants that the opportunity is to take us out of our bubble and think about the reach, application, and implications of this medium for society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first research presenter was &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/himabatavia&#34;&gt;Hima Batavia&lt;/a&gt;, Research Assistant at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrcglobal.org/&#34;&gt;McLaughlin-Rotman Centre for Global Health and Earth Institute&lt;/a&gt; at Columbia University.  Her talk &amp;ldquo;Mobile Health: the Great Equalizer&amp;rdquo; focused on mobile health and showcased 7 examples including:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s Go Time &gt;&gt; ChangeMedium Toronto</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/its-go-time-changemedium-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 15:11:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/its-go-time-changemedium-toronto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s go time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChangeMedium Toronto is slated for October 24th at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/MaRS-Centre.html&#34;&gt;MaRS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;What is it?&lt;/em&gt; Read more to find out. &lt;em&gt;Want a hand in it?&lt;/em&gt; Leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
ChangeMedium&lt;/strong&gt; is an initiative to provoke public micro-messaging as a medium for change. Public micro-messaging (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}) is emerging as &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post436&#34;&gt;the most accessible, participatory public medium in history&lt;/a&gt;. Bringing the open and emergent properties of the web to the global reach of text messaging is already showing great potential for public benefit. But we&amp;rsquo;ve only begun to understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening let alone build an infrastructure to make the most of this medium. Enter ChangeMedium Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoCap09 – a journey, my mission.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/socap09-a-journey-my-mission./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 21:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/socap09-a-journey-my-mission./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin:1em;display:block&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 240px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/11641964@N06/3865017114/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2443/3865017114_cea1d1d858_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;DSC02987&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; fetchpriority=&#34;high&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;228&#34; alt=&#34;DSC02987&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image by ***Images*** via Flickr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;Coming to &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialcapitalmarkets.net&#34;&gt;SoCap09&lt;/a&gt; has proved to be a good opportunity to integrate a number of threads I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring over the past few years. Accelerated by a&lt;a href=&#34;http://complexityrising.tumblr.com/post/156072054/wise-investments-mission-impact&#34;&gt;n exploration&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sifteverything.com/about/jeremy-heigh/&#34;&gt;Jeremy Heigh&lt;/a&gt; and crystalized through provocative conversations with &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/stephenhuddart&#34;&gt;Stephen Huddart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salzburgglobal.org/2009/includes/FacultyPopUp.cfm?IDSPECIAL_EVENT=371&amp;amp;IDRecords=20038&#34;&gt;Tom Reis&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s the perspective I now find myself now arriving with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know &lt;strong&gt;complexity is rising and change is quickening&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theory-talks.org/2008/08/theory-talk-13.html&#34;&gt;systems of society&lt;/a&gt; are reaching their limits. Our interventions are having more impact. &lt;strong&gt;Repercussions ripple &lt;a href=&#34;http://complexityrising.tumblr.com/post/170530616/snapshot-of-complexity-theory&#34;&gt;up, down, across systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reason – a manifesto for impact investment.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reason-a-manifesto-for-impact-investment./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 23:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reason-a-manifesto-for-impact-investment./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
:::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin:1em;display:block&amp;rdquo;}
::: {}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Anton_Tschechow_Denkmal.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Bust of Chekhov at Badenweiler&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/fa/Anton_Tschechow_Denkmal.JPG&#34; title=&#34;Bust of Chekhov at Badenweiler&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;445&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Anton_Tschechow_Denkmal.JPG&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
:::
::::&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post an experiment in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.siftstar.com/precision-manifesto/&#34;&gt;co-posting&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; with thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.siftstar.com/about-sift/&#34;&gt;Jeremy Heigh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact is no reason to invest. Impact is an outcome.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Investment is a choice. A choice for a reason. A choice of reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason is not static. Reason evolves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Teach a person to fish, they fish. Pond gets over-fished, they go hungry. Every system is part of other systems. Every action affects others. Nothing stays the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I am not a tool” – Twitter’s inflection of web and society.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/i-am-not-a-tool-twitters-inflection-of-web-and-society./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 21:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/i-am-not-a-tool-twitters-inflection-of-web-and-society./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
:::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin:1em;display:block&amp;rdquo;}
::: {}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Wag_85-1_points_inflection.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Points of inflection.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/29/Wag_85-1_points_inflection.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Points of inflection.&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;98&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;152&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Wag_85-1_points_inflection.jpg&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
:::
::::&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update (090811-20:51ET): The end felt incomplete &amp;ndash; some more detail added.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some questions about how public micro-messaging is different than other social media. Why is it not just another tool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the flip answer of &amp;ldquo;well it&amp;rsquo;s public and micro and that&amp;rsquo;s the difference&amp;rdquo; is correct what is more elusive is how that is changing things &amp;ndash; an inflection in the web &amp;ndash; and society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Framing our future: SoCap09</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/framing-our-future-socap09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 02:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/framing-our-future-socap09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;I&#39;m looking forward to this year&#39;s [Social Capital Markets conference](http://socialcapitalmarkets.net). [Last year](http://socialfinance.ca/blog/2008/12/opportunity-amidst-crisis-a-recap-of-social-capital-markets-conf/) I came way with a sense of a movement -- a long term movement that was working with the balance of social and financial objectives in service of a better world for all. I&#39;m sure this year will do much of the same -- bringing the best of the movement together to share their progress and inspire those who are looking to explore &#39;the intersection of money and meaning&#39;. If you are interested in this space, [it&#39;s the place to be](https://www.reg-services.com/socialcapitalmedia/socap09/).
&lt;p&gt;This year though, I&amp;rsquo;m going with a more ambitious agenda. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.margolin-consulting.com/about.html&#34;&gt;Jessica Margolin&lt;/a&gt; hit on something in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.margolin-consulting.com/2009/08/socap09.html&#34;&gt;her SoCap09 post&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; encapsulated in these 2 quotes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remediating the web for action.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/remediating-the-web-for-action./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 15:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/remediating-the-web-for-action./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 1em; display: block;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 240px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:10mm-aggregate.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/e/e6/10mm-aggregate.jpg/300px-10mm-aggregate.jpg&#34; title=&#34;10mm graded crushed rock or aggregate, for use...&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; alt=&#34;10mm graded crushed rock or aggregate, for use...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image via Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve become inundated with destinations, places to go, placess to post, places to read and place to make change&amp;hellip; and the effort of aggregators seem largely only to have added another destination. And every destination seems to want us to have a conversation there. Well that&amp;rsquo;s not really working either because there are just too many places asking us for conversation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter and the emerging medium for change -&gt; “What are you doing?”</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/twitter-and-the-emerging-medium-for-change-what-are-you-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/twitter-and-the-emerging-medium-for-change-what-are-you-doing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is giving rise to the most accessible, participatory public medium in history. The implications for social change, innovation, and entrepreneurship are huge but hardly explored. In the coming paragraphs I explain what I see and call out to you, to all, to help surface what&amp;rsquo;s happening and understand how it can help us create the world we want. I care because &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post156&#34;&gt;we need change like never before.&lt;/a&gt; If that matters to you too, please read, comment, and share. Let&amp;rsquo;s see where this goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free the Fail Whale!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/free-the-fail-whale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 17:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/free-the-fail-whale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to &lt;a href=&#34;http://tumblog.igniter.com/post/110968319/on-the-one-hand-the-member-financial-institutions&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;pull a VISA&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and free the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whatisfailwhale.info/&#34;&gt;Fail Whale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the early days of credit cards, the banks were facing competitive and processing challenges. A number of them came together create this thing called &lt;a href=&#34;http://visa.com&#34;&gt;VISA&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; an idea to develop and provide common standards and processing infrastructure for their competing cards. Well I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to do it again for this thing called public micro-messaging. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The social venture financing landscape.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-financing-landscape./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 01:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-financing-landscape./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m hearing people talking about mission/purpose/values in the venture investing world more frequently. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t really be a surprise given the tectonic shifts in the systems of our society. From some perspectives it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;the right thing to do&amp;rdquo;. From others it&amp;rsquo;s a straight-forward commercial opportunity with good market fundamentals. What is often surprising to folks however is how much is already underway and who is involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://marsdd.com&#34;&gt;MaRS&lt;/a&gt; released a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.marsdd.com/2009/04/24/social-venture-financing/&#34;&gt;white-paper&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s a great primer for those that are interested. It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of what&amp;rsquo;s sure to be a great series and if you are interested in digging more into this area there&amp;rsquo;s plenty to start with over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialfinance.ca&#34;&gt;SocialFinance.ca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dead or Alive – the future of ‘hashtags’</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/dead-or-alive-the-future-of-hashtags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/dead-or-alive-the-future-of-hashtags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {}
A couple of weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://scobleizer.com/&#34;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt; had a epiphany that &lt;a href=&#34;http://beta.friendfeed.com/scobleizer/bb5b11fd/i-just-realized-hash-tags-are-dead-er-less&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;hashtags are dead&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;. That epiphany was really more about realtime search than the future of hashtags. If anything, inline tags (hashtags) are going to be an increasingly important aspect of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post412&#34;&gt;realtime web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline tags are simply the combination of a unique character and a keyword (e.g. #tag).  Introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/person/chris-messina&#34; title=&#34;Chris Messina&#34;&gt;Chris Messina&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;crunchbase&amp;rdquo;} back in 2007, hashtags have seen increasing usage around current events, conversation and collaboration. Here&amp;rsquo;s what makes them uniquely valuable, particularly in the public micro-message:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The real-time web. Game on!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-real-time-web.-game-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 17:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-real-time-web.-game-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Popularized by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, the public micro-messaging medium is leading to a major evolution of the web and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is just the beginning of this real-time internet &amp;ndash; the simplest manifestation of this long term trend &amp;ndash; that spells the end of communications and start of an interaction society. ~ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gigaom.com&#34; title=&#34;Om Malik&#34;&gt;Om Malik&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, &lt;a href=&#34;http://omis.me/2009/04/14/what-twitter-broadband-internet-mean-to-me/%20&#34;&gt;What Twitter and Broadband Mean to Me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public micro-message medium represents the potential for a 4 billion person global message board, where anyone can share their interests, ideas, and actions real-time, and where every message can be seen, referenced, and responded to by anyone directly, person to person. &lt;strong&gt;This is nothing short of monumental.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new foundation for distributed collaboration and collective intelligence.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-new-foundation-for-distributed-collaboration-and-collective-intelligence./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 15:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-new-foundation-for-distributed-collaboration-and-collective-intelligence./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_410&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-410&#34; style=&#34;width: 155px&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;figcaption aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;Threading Twitter, Weaving the Web.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been an exciting year in the development of &lt;a href=&#34;http://svcommons.com&#34;&gt;the Social Venture Commons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://shldlss.com&#34;&gt;Shouldless Inc.&lt;/a&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot and believe what we contributing to the emergence of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post355&#34;&gt;public micro-messages as a new foundation for distributed collaboration&lt;/a&gt; and collective intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has been experiencing &lt;a href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2009/03/16/twitter-growth-rate-versus-facebook/&#34;&gt;extraordinary growth&lt;/a&gt; and the the use of #hashtags has enabled a new dimension. As we tag, we build threads. These threads weave throughout the Twittersphere, linking interests, communities and conversations. As we tag we&amp;rsquo;re collectively weaving a tapestry that both describes our world and crafts the edges of what creates it. Over time I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by the potential reach threads can have and see them as a launch-pad for new collaborations. And as these things happen, I can only imagine what these threads will be able to tell us about our selves and where the world is going. Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alpha, Beta… Public</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/alpha-beta-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 14:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/alpha-beta-public/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
In this world where web apps can be built, launched and iterated quickly we&amp;rsquo;re seeing more and more of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perpetual_beta&#34; title=&#34;Perpetual beta&#34;&gt;perpetual beta&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;}. Even most of googles apps carry the &amp;lsquo;beta&amp;rsquo; tag long past when my usage experience seems to be bug free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One side of me says, forget the distinction&amp;hellip; of course it&amp;rsquo;s always beta&amp;hellip; if it&amp;rsquo;s not it&amp;rsquo;s not evolving. Another side, says it&amp;rsquo;s about managing expectations, as in &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t throw things at your computer (or me) if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as you want it to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguring my presence and channels.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reconfiguring-my-presence-and-channels./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 19:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reconfiguring-my-presence-and-channels./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been unsubscribing from email subscriptions like crazy lately and have just been prompted to review my online profiles in prep for the launch of http://thread.IO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to want product/org updates to come to me&amp;hellip; ones that I had requested. That seems to be changing though. I&amp;rsquo;m shifting to reliance on curation and synchronicity like never before. That means relying on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}, Friendfeed, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tumblelog&#34; title=&#34;Tumblelog&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} and direct notices from real people who know me to find out what&amp;rsquo;s going on. It marks my trust that what needs to, will find me. This is big. And I think it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection of how the social web is fundamentally changing us. I don&amp;rsquo;t want new destinations I want humanly pre-filtered inputs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inline tagging and the next semantic web.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/inline-tagging-and-the-next-semantic-web./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 16:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/inline-tagging-and-the-next-semantic-web./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I loved &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/mingyeow/discovery-is-the-new-cocaine-going-beyond-engagement&#34;&gt;this presentation&lt;/a&gt; on Discovery by the Mr. Tweet folks. And today Fred Wilson had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2009/02/hasnt-it-always-been-about-status.html&#34;&gt;great post on the value of &amp;lsquo;status updates&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;ve been calling it micro-messaging).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been taken with the use of inline tagging as a way to enhance discovery and it&amp;rsquo;s power. On twitter the @ reply and the # tag are great examples. What we&amp;rsquo;re doing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://VenTwits.com&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; and GroupTwits (coming soon) is adding tags that identify entities, groups, and topics. I&amp;rsquo;m no semantic expert but I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by how people are starting to use it. In Toronto, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/peer-production-primer-presentation&#34;&gt;#hohoto story&lt;/a&gt; and around the world we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the power of tags like &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23gaza&#34;&gt;#gaza&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The proprietary/open balance in startup mode.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-proprietary/open-balance-in-startup-mode./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 19:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-proprietary/open-balance-in-startup-mode./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
:::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 1em; display: block;&amp;rdquo;}
::: {}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Strategic_Planning_Symbol.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Marine Institute Ireland, Strategic_Planning_S...&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/bd/Strategic_Planning_Symbol.jpg/202px-Strategic_Planning_Symbol.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Marine Institute Ireland, Strategic_Planning_S...&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;115&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;202&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Strategic_Planning_Symbol.jpg&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;
:::
::::&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post350&#34;&gt;written some before&lt;/a&gt; on our efforts to peer-produce &lt;a href=&#34;http://shldlss.com&#34;&gt;Shouldess Inc.&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com/ventures/%5Eshldlss&#34;&gt;^shldlss&lt;/a&gt;), the developer of &lt;a href=&#34;http://VenTwits.com&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; and the for-profit cohort of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://svcommons.com&#34;&gt;Social Venture Commons&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com/ventures/%5Esvc&#34;&gt;^svc&lt;/a&gt;). We&amp;rsquo;ve decided to launch early and iterate rapidly with VenTwits and its group focused cousin GroupTwits (to be turned on soon). We&amp;rsquo;re also planning to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source&#34; title=&#34;Open source&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} our code once we&amp;rsquo;ve rebuilt a core based on how people actually use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Researching Twitter Magic</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/researching-twitter-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 18:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/researching-twitter-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
:::: {.zemanta-img style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 1em; display: block;&amp;rdquo;}
::: {}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/company/twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Image representing Twitter as depicted in Crun...&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/assets/images/resized/0000/2755/2755v2-max-450x450.png&#34; title=&#34;Image representing Twitter as depicted in Crun...&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;49&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;210&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com&#34;&gt;CrunchBase&lt;/a&gt;
:::
::::&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you love it, hate it or otherwise, there is something unique enabled through &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;}. I think there is something interesting and potentially powerful happening and seem to have ranted well enough to get the interest of &lt;a href=&#34;http://sigeneration.ca/people_frances_westley_en.htm&#34;&gt;Dr. Frances Westley&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.ca/Getting-Maybe-How-World-Changed/dp/0679314431&#34;&gt;Getting to Maybe &amp;ndash; How the World is Changed&lt;/a&gt;, a member of &lt;a href=&#34;http://sigeneration.ca&#34;&gt;Social Innovation Generation&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sig.uwaterloo.ca/&#34;&gt;Chair of Social Innovation at University of Waterloo&lt;/a&gt;. Frances asked me to articulate my hunches from which we&amp;rsquo;ll see what might be the most interesting research questions that someone from her team could dig in to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VenTwits is alive and the adventure begins.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/ventwits-is-alive-and-the-adventure-begins./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 21:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/ventwits-is-alive-and-the-adventure-begins./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
This really began back at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://startupempire.ca/&#34;&gt;StartupEmpire conference&lt;/a&gt; on November 14th, 2008 in the midst of &lt;a href=&#34;http://howardlindzon.com&#34;&gt;Howard Lindzon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://StockTwits.com&#34;&gt;StockTwits&lt;/a&gt; presentation.  Today, &lt;a href=&#34;http://VenTwits.com&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com/ventures/%5Eventwits&#34;&gt;^VenTwits&lt;/a&gt;) is live as a the first property in a series of initiatives to help things happen and create the world we want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/ventwits-puagku.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/ventwits-puagku.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://shldlss.com&#34;&gt;Shouldless Inc.&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com/ventures/%5Eshldlss&#34;&gt;^shldlss&lt;/a&gt;), VenTwits is a site for people building things they care about. We believe there is something special about communications that happen in public, 140 characters at a time. It seems to encourage a unique breadth and practicality of engagement such as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hohoto.ca&#34;&gt;#hohoto&lt;/a&gt; party in Toronto. #hohoto emerged through &lt;a href=&#34;http://Twitter.com&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/peer-production-primer-presentation&#34;&gt;SlideShare preso&lt;/a&gt;) and within 18 days of the first mention was sold-out to over 600 people, raised $25,000 in cash and 2 tonnes of food for Toronto&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailybread.ca/&#34;&gt;Daily Bread Foodbank&lt;/a&gt;. All this without any one leader or cash investment &amp;ndash; rather it leveraged parallel leadership from over a dozen people and the contributions of countless more. What if we could leverage what happened there?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started on VenTwits</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/getting-started-on-ventwits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 19:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/getting-started-on-ventwits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/ventwits-puagku.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://lewwwk.com/images/ventwits-puagku.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; is about people building the things they care about. It came from seeing the potential in &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; as a medium for discovery, connection, and practical engagement. With VenTwits we hope it can help you find new ventures you are interested, give you an opportunity to participate, and simply help things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started, simply &lt;a href=&#34;http://ventwits.com&#34;&gt;login to VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; once using your Twitter user name and password. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t on twitter there is a link right there where you can sign-up quickly and easily. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve logged in for the first time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ventwitsapp&#34;&gt;VenTwits&lt;/a&gt; knows to follow you and look for anything you tweet that uses a VenTwits tag. From that point on, you can tweet through the site, through Twitter, or whichever way you twitter best.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Partnership in Peer-Production</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/organizational-partnership-in-peer-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 22:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/organizational-partnership-in-peer-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
In taking a peer-produced approach to building the Social Venture Commons and shldlss (the for-profit offshoot), I&amp;rsquo;m seeing the power of individual contributions. Peer-production is driven by interest and passion &amp;ndash; truly personal things, and in doing things in a peer-produced manner, financial and intellectual capital aren&amp;rsquo;t as all-powerful. All this has me thinking about organizational partnerships differently and paying more attention to the fact that organizations generally have a lot of individuals working for them &amp;ndash; the real resource that seems to make peer-production thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kudos for Equity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/kudos-for-equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 21:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/kudos-for-equity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Owning equity in a for-profit venture is a powerful motivator &amp;ndash; particularly in the early stages.  It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most contentious, negotiated parts of building a high-growth venture. This comes from our organizational conventions of control and scarcity &amp;ndash; we need to control and amass resources to control and weild power and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In taking a peer-produced approach to building Shldlss, the for-profit offshoot of the Social Venture Commons, I found we needed a new model to fairly attribute the economic value to those who actually created it. After many conversations, including on &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post350&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;m at with what has now become our &amp;ldquo;Kudos Model&amp;rdquo; for economic value distribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quick update on the Social Venture Commons (#svc)</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-quick-update-on-the-social-venture-commons-%23svc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 04:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-quick-update-on-the-social-venture-commons-%23svc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been head-down these last 2 weeks and we&amp;rsquo;re making great progress toward first launch.  For the latest action on the Social Venture Commons &amp;ndash; feel free to track the &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23svc&#34;&gt;twitter stream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model for distributing founding equity among those that contribute is essentially set, and I&amp;rsquo;ve begun receiving investor commitments on both the charitable and for-profit side. Development has been greatly augmented with the code-mastery of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/j_dan_williams&#34;&gt;Dan Williams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will post some more fulsome reports next week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opportunity ’09: micro-messaging based collaboration</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/opportunity-09-micro-messaging-based-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 18:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/opportunity-09-micro-messaging-based-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: zemanta-img&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 182px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Capsicum0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fd/Capsicum0.jpg/202px-Capsicum0.jpg&#34; title=&#34;A ripe red jalapeño cut open to show the seeds&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;182&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; alt=&#34;A ripe red jalapeño cut open to show the seeds&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image via Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;My focus heading into 2009 is micro-messaging based collaboration. From where I sit I think it will have a profound effect on &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post75&#34;&gt;the way we organize&lt;/a&gt; resources &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post62&#34;&gt;to get things done&lt;/a&gt; and will mark a fundamental shift in shape of the organizations and systems of our future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Convo” on the shift</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-convo-on-the-shift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 17:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-convo-on-the-shift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 234px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rycoleman/3101993357/&#34; title=&#34;Convo01-7579.jpg by Ryan Coleman, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3254/3101993357_475ea51179.jpg&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; fetchpriority=&#34;high&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; alt=&#34;Convo01-7579.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;photo by: Ryan Coleman&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago a few loosely connected people gathered for a conversation &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://theconvo.wikispaces.com&#34;&gt;the #convo&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23convo&#34;&gt;tweetstream&lt;/a&gt;). Most I hadn&amp;rsquo;t met before &amp;ndash; except through twitter &amp;ndash; but the conversation is still with me seems to have woven into some really great places in Toronto&amp;rsquo;s twittersphere like &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23thmvmnt&#34;&gt;#thmvmnt&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23changecamp&#34;&gt;#changecamp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23tsTO&#34;&gt;#tsTO&lt;/a&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap of what my memory and chicken-scratch allow and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping some more fulsome records emerge in addition to the great &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23convo&#34;&gt;tweetstream&lt;/a&gt; and photos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peer-producing a for-profit startup.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/peer-producing-a-for-profit-startup./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 21:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/peer-producing-a-for-profit-startup./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tjt195/113596431/&#34; title=&#34;Ant Party by tarotastic, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/53/113596431_63b3f82285.jpg&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; fetchpriority=&#34;high&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; alt=&#34;Ant Party&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;By tarotastic (tjt195 on flickr)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with peer-producing the first for-profit property coming out of the social venture commons. So far I&amp;rsquo;m finding once again that there is no better way to learn than to try doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s different about bringing &amp;lsquo;peer-producion&amp;rsquo; into the mix? Well so far the difference I&amp;rsquo;ve most experienced is the degree to which I&amp;rsquo;m compelled to share what I&amp;rsquo;m working on at this early stage. It&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to but it is getting more people involved and having a definite impact on how the idea forms and how quickly it becomes reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Venture Commons – in development</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-commons-in-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 07:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-commons-in-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::: entry-content
Things have been moving quickly in the last few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that we&amp;rsquo;re in development on the Social Venture Commons. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a more descriptive presentation below and have also included a brief primer on peer production of organizations (a quick snapshot of the #hohoto holiday party in Toronto).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on initial partnerships for the commons and am getting ready to reach out for seed investment for one of the for-profit properties (VenTwits.com).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving Democracy: a call to Canadians to step up!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reviving-democracy-a-call-to-canadians-to-step-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 21:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reviving-democracy-a-call-to-canadians-to-step-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: zemanta-img&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34; style=&#34;width: 240px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/22168167@N00/2076448655&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2056/2076448655_1b96031474_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Drapeau du Canada à la Citadelle de Québec&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; alt=&#34;Drapeau du Canada à la Citadelle de Québec&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image by abdallahh via Flickr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;My interest in politics and democracy hit record levels recently. November was hope inspired with the victory of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://change.gov/&#34;&gt;Obama&lt;/a&gt; movement and then by a revolt in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parl.gc.ca/&#34;&gt;House of Commons&lt;/a&gt; in Canada. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gg.ca/menu_e.asp&#34;&gt;Governor General&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s decision to prorogue sparked a visceral anger unlike any I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in a long time. To me it was a technically legitimate assault on the core of our democracy &amp;ndash; blatantly ignoring the voice of the people that we voted to represent us &amp;ndash; the members of the House.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro-funds: Peer-producing Venture Capital (UPDATE 1)</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/micro-funds-peer-producing-venture-capital-update-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 06:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/micro-funds-peer-producing-venture-capital-update-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Here&amp;rsquo;s my first crack at the Micro-Funds concept.  It&amp;rsquo;s related to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post339&#34;&gt;Social Venture Commons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post277&#34;&gt;Social Capital&lt;/a&gt; work I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing. They are all based on the &lt;a href=&#34;../?s=organizing+mode&#34;&gt;new mode of organizing&lt;/a&gt; I see emerging.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
*** I&amp;rsquo;ve also added an illustration of 3 alternative models that have emerged in recent conversations. They are all interesting in their own right and it may be more about using them in according to specific situations. All comments/suggestions/alternatives welcome. ***&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/3113972750/&#34; title=&#34;Micro-fund Model Alternatives by Michael Lewkowitz, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Micro-fund Model Alternatives&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3143/3113972750_9743af482c.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;294&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The convo I’d like to have: w &#43; ppo &#43; d &gt;&gt; our future</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-convo-id-like-to-have-w--ppo--d-our-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 15:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-convo-id-like-to-have-w--ppo--d-our-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
*** &lt;a href=&#34;http://theconvo.wikispaces.com&#34;&gt;SESSION WIKI&lt;/a&gt; NOW LIVE ***&lt;br&gt;
Those who know me know that this is a persistent theme with me &amp;ndash; and now provoked by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/josephdee&#34;&gt;@josephdee&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time to take this into a more focused conversation with a few more folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Premise:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way of the world is &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post156&#34;&gt;borked&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web (among other things) is shifting the way we organize resources, ourselves and create new things (&lt;strong&gt;W&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From that (in part) is emerging a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/?s=mode+org+resource&#34;&gt;new mode of organizing&lt;/a&gt; where the organization itself (not just the product) is peer produced (&lt;strong&gt;PP0&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design&#34; title=&#34;Design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} is the essential process of intentionally creating things (&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Un-borking&amp;rsquo; our world means creating our future through &lt;strong&gt;W+PPO+D&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conversation I&amp;rsquo;d like to have:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechStars “Hollyhocked”</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/techstars-hollyhocked/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 22:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/techstars-hollyhocked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/company/techstars&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Image representing TechStars as depicted in Cr...&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/assets/images/resized/0000/4033/4033v1-max-450x450.png&#34; title=&#34;Image representing TechStars as depicted in Cr...&#34;&gt;{.alignleft decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;46&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;60&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://techstars.org&#34; title=&#34;TechStars&#34;&gt;TechStars&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} before and never thought too much about it &amp;ndash; &amp;lsquo;another incubator&amp;rsquo; is how I filed it. Well one of my highlights from StartupEmpire was hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/person/david-cohen&#34; title=&#34;David Cohen&#34;&gt;David Cohen&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;crunchbase&amp;rdquo;} of TechStars. Half-way through it struck me&amp;hellip; why don&amp;rsquo;t we do a TechStars for Social Ventures at Hollyhock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Venture Commons: Primer Presentation</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-commons-primer-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 04:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-social-venture-commons-primer-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Building on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/tag/social-venture-commons&#34;&gt;previous posts&lt;/a&gt; about the Social Venture Commons here&amp;rsquo;s a draft overview of what&amp;rsquo;s been brewing. This venture is one part of my trio to support the ventures working from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/?s=organizing+mode&#34;&gt;new mode of organizing&lt;/a&gt; I see emerging. The two other pieces are the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post320&#34;&gt;micro-funds&lt;/a&gt; [(presentation coming soon)]{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration: line-through;&amp;rdquo;} which is a modified version of early-stage venture/angel investing and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_capital&#34; title=&#34;Social capital&#34;&gt;social capital&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} learning project (in development for a trio of venture networks) based in part on &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post277&#34;&gt;the thinking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewal2 – Open to Foundations</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/renewal2-open-to-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 13:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/renewal2-open-to-foundations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://renewal2.ca&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://img.skitch.com/20081117-qeqmtc6stc971aty2r213sjgxs.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Renewal2 Investment Fund&#34;&gt;{.alignright decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;80&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;281&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;I recently received an update from Renewal on the development of their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.renewal2.ca/&#34;&gt;Renewal2 Investment Fund&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to hearing that the fundraising is going well in-spite of the financial crisis, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to learn that they have created an investment structure that makes it easier for foundations and others to invest across North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting time for foundations, and some like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wkkf.org/default.aspx?LanguageID=0&#34;&gt;W.K. Kellogg Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gatesfoundation.org/Pages/home.aspx&#34;&gt;Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt; are making bold moves by setting up their own &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wkkf.org/default.aspx?tabid=1152&amp;amp;CID=415&amp;amp;NID=268&amp;amp;LanguageID=0&#34;&gt;venture funds&lt;/a&gt; or indicating that they are moving toward spending down (vs. preserving endowments). I hope that some more foundations take these steps and look to investing in funds like Renewal2 to spur the different forms of innovation that are possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obama – the mindset tips.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/obama-the-mindset-tips./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/obama-the-mindset-tips./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 214px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/84992687@N00/3004717988&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3004/3004717988_06761377b7_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;the 44th President of the United States...Bara...&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; fetchpriority=&#34;high&#34; width=&#34;214&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;the 44th President of the United States...Bara...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image by jmtimages via Flickr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;A major moment in history last night &amp;ndash; a shift in the trajectory of our civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not because of the firsts, the stats, or the policies. It&amp;rsquo;s where this comes from and how it came about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about a shift in mindset in the most dominant society in our civilization. A shift from fear to hope. From divisiveness to inclusion. From independent to interdependent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions of trust in connections.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/dimensions-of-trust-in-connections./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 18:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/dimensions-of-trust-in-connections./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 240px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/49503180180@N01/2982599450/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3184/2982599450_d646a1f73a_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;You can!!&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;159&#34; alt=&#34;You can!!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image by cuellar via Flickr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;I recently had an impromptu conversation on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/55443758/exploring-trust&#34;&gt;nature of trust&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;my tumblog&lt;/a&gt; with my fellow &amp;lsquo;social catalysts&amp;rsquo; (more info coming soon). I&amp;rsquo;m fairly new to exploring this topic in this way so really appreciated the depth of responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insights I&amp;rsquo;m left with are that there are essentially 3 dimensions to trust in facilitating a connection. Each dimension is a range that might be expressed as follows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expanding on the Social Venture Commons</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/expanding-on-the-social-venture-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 00:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/expanding-on-the-social-venture-commons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Expanding on my previous &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post271&#34;&gt;post on micro-funds and the social venture commons&lt;/a&gt;, here are few more pieces on what I see being the core elements of the Social Venture Commons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;First, I see the commons containing three interdependent realms:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conversations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;accomplishments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accomplishments are the product and desired outcomes of every venture. They are also a great catalyst of conversation. Conversation, in turn, is a great catalyst of connections &amp;ndash; connections to ideas, resources, people etc. And connections, in turn, catalyze accomplishments &amp;ndash; new resources to help get things done better, faster, etc. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s not that linear but I do sense a compelling interrelationship and even flow there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging Social Capital</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/supercharging-social-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/supercharging-social-capital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with some fantastic colleagues (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/duncanwork&#34;&gt;Duncan Work&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ica-associates.ca/Template/Foundations/DHprofile.cfm&#34;&gt;Duncan Holmes&lt;/a&gt;) on ways to harness &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_capital&#34; title=&#34;Social capital&#34;&gt;social capital&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} (the relationship kind vs. financial kind). For me, the interest is applying it to ventures that are working toward a just and sustainable society &amp;ndash; but, more generally, I believe it is our most underutilized form or capital and is becoming increasingly important in the current economic downturn and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post75&#34;&gt;new mode of organization&lt;/a&gt; that I see emerging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micro-funds and the Social Venture Commons</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/micro-funds-and-the-social-venture-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 17:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/micro-funds-and-the-social-venture-commons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
Working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post246&#34;&gt;the building blocks for a new kind of venture capital&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been shaping a couple of core components &amp;ndash; micro funds, and the social venture commons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Micro-funds:&lt;/strong&gt; making small, flexible, intuitive, low-cost, high-leverage investments. Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short life:&lt;/strong&gt; fully invested within 3 years or less&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small, high-leverage investments:&lt;/strong&gt; invest financial (e.g. $25-50k) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_capital&#34; title=&#34;Social capital&#34;&gt;social capital&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} in high-leverage ways &amp;ndash; core capacity, incremental engagement, financial seeding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low or no fee:&lt;/strong&gt; offset with performance based incentives for financial and impact returns appropriate to the fund&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light-weight and dynamic operations:&lt;/strong&gt; led by individuals or organizations that have a unique position or perspective on the &amp;lsquo;frontiers&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; run as a &amp;lsquo;side-car&amp;rsquo; to existing occupation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commons interdependent:&lt;/strong&gt; fund and individual investments must spark and support a conversation and generally contribute to and engage community to mitigate risk, improve success, and demonstrate returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoCap08 – Alive online</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/socap08-alive-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 14:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/socap08-alive-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: thumbnail
&lt;a href=&#34;http://skitch.com/igniter/2wgq/social-capital-markets-model&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Social Capital Markets Model&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://img.skitch.com/20081014-c68padjjcg4tsjctsf4x9tqgjp.preview.jpg&#34;&gt;{.alignright decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;218&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;380&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;[]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-size: 10px; font-family: Lucida Grande,Trebuchet,sans-serif,Helvetica,Arial; color: #808080;&amp;quot;}My first impression of &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialcapitalmarkets.net&#34;&gt;SoCap08&lt;/a&gt; have as much to do with the excellence of the physical event as they do with the virtualization of it.
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First the physical event. There are over 600 participants from the usual people but also from more mainstream financial players that are seriously starting to get their toes wet. I first heard about this a year ago when Kevin Jones of &lt;a href=&#34;http://goodcap.net&#34;&gt;GoodCapital&lt;/a&gt; was just starting to pull it together and I must say they did an extraordinary job of convening the community in a big way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Blocks for a new kind of Venture Capital</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/building-blocks-for-a-new-kind-of-venture-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 19:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/building-blocks-for-a-new-kind-of-venture-capital/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34; style=&#34;width: 202px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Banknotes.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/09/Banknotes.jpg/202px-Banknotes.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Banknotes from all around the World donated by...&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;202&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; alt=&#34;Banknotes from all around the World donated by...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image via Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A new kind of venture capital for purposeful ventures is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring for a number of years and was recently reenergized by some conversations at the OpenEverything retreat in September. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this now as I head to SoCap08 and looking forward to testing some of these ideas against other emerging models (e.g. Enterpreneur Commons) and amongst the worlds leaders in social venture investment. I&amp;rsquo;ll follow-up this post with any big insights that emerge and in the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m interested in any comments about what I&amp;rsquo;ve started framing below. Feel free to contribute in the comments or email me directly. And of course if you are buliding another model &amp;ndash; feel free to take anything you gain from this and use or remix freely &amp;ndash; just ping me and let me know what you are working on and share alike.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SoCap08 – Social Capital Markets Conference</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/socap08-social-capital-markets-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 02:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/socap08-social-capital-markets-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to head to &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialcapitalmarkets.net&#34;&gt;SoCap08&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=37.7793,-122.4192&amp;amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;amp;q=37.7793,-122.4192%20%28San%20Francisco%2C%20California%29&amp;amp;t=h&#34; title=&#34;San Francisco, California&#34;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;geolocation&amp;rdquo;}. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief blurb on what it&amp;rsquo;s about &amp;ndash; and for those of you who are interested there is a twitter &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/socap08&#34;&gt;account&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23socap08&#34;&gt;tag&lt;/a&gt; that you can follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing well and doing good&lt;/strong&gt; is the mantra of a new generation of entrepreneurs and the organizations that invest in them. And Social Capital Markets 2008 (SoCap08) is a new event designed to bring together all of the people and organizations with a similar deep passion to change the world through sustainable businesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the midst of a macroshift.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/in-the-midst-of-a-macroshift./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 03:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/in-the-midst-of-a-macroshift./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s clear that the financial system built on the mindset of the last few decades is unravelling.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quotes like these are increasingly common in the media. So what is the mindset we need to build the new system? In his prescient book Macroshift, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34; title=&#34;Ervin László&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} suggests what I think would be a good start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From competition&amp;hellip; to reconciliation and partnership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From greed and scarcity&amp;hellip; to sufficiency and caring&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparkin’ up our future leaders.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/sparkin-up-our-future-leaders./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 00:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/sparkin-up-our-future-leaders./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
I was invited by Maria Antonakos of &lt;a href=&#34;http://opusphilanthropy.com&#34;&gt;Opus Philanthropy&lt;/a&gt; to speak to her Philanthropy class in the Commerce program at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DeGroote_School_of_Business&#34; title=&#34;DeGroote School of Business&#34;&gt;DeGroote School of Business&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} at &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=43.2625,-79.9225&amp;amp;spn=0.01,0.01&amp;amp;q=43.2625,-79.9225%20%28McMaster%20University%29&amp;amp;t=h&#34; title=&#34;McMaster University&#34;&gt;McMaster University&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;geolocation&amp;rdquo;} in &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=43.2552777778,-79.8730555556&amp;amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;amp;q=43.2552777778,-79.8730555556%20%28Hamilton%2C%20Ontario%29&amp;amp;t=h&#34; title=&#34;Hamilton, Ontario&#34;&gt;Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;geolocation&amp;rdquo;}. She asked me to talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_finance&#34; title=&#34;Social finance&#34;&gt;social finance&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} and &amp;lsquo;a little bit about how you ended up doing what you do&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prepared the short presentation below to give the overview of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_finance&#34;&gt;social finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_enterprise&#34; title=&#34;Social enterprise&#34;&gt;social enterprise&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;}, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_innovation&#34;&gt;social innovation&lt;/a&gt; but somehow ended up getting into some fun rants about making choices to venture toward a just and sustainable society. I learned that they were just beginning to make their career choices and over the conversation I realized what an extraordinary privilege we have in our society to take risks and know that if we fail there is a strong support structure around us. Our main fears of failure relate to ego &amp;ndash; not survival. Ironic really because if we don&amp;rsquo;t take risks and venture forward to create a better future we are playing with the possibility that we actually put our survival at stake. A bit drastic maybe but worth a thought. Bottom line, while some think that now&amp;rsquo;s a terrible time to start a business, if it&amp;rsquo;s a social venture I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s ever been a better time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenEverything Video</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 00:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
We were fortunate enough to have Duane Nikull of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adobe.com&#34; title=&#34;Adobe Systems&#34;&gt;Adobe&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} do a Duane&amp;rsquo;s World episode on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki&#34;&gt;OpenEverything Retreat&lt;/a&gt; at Hollyhock.  Another fun perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The parallels of Web 2.0 with the Open Source and Social Innovation threads</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-parallels-of-web-2.0-with-the-open-source-and-social-innovation-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 02:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-parallels-of-web-2.0-with-the-open-source-and-social-innovation-threads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osbr.ca/ojs/index.php/osbr/issue/view/67&#34;&gt;The recent issue&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osbr.ca&#34;&gt;Open Source Business Review&lt;/a&gt; is all about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_innovation&#34; title=&#34;Social innovation&#34;&gt;Social Innovation&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} &amp;ndash; what appears to be a an experiment in seeing how these two memes both converge and diverge. (hat tip to &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonspace.wordpress.com/about/&#34;&gt;Mark Surman&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonspace.wordpress.com/2008/09/25/constellation-model-in-open-source-business-review/&#34;&gt;pointing me there&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, this convergence is not unique to those fields. The quotes below from a recent post by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchbase.com/person/brad-burnham&#34; title=&#34;Brad Burnham&#34;&gt;Brad Burnham&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;crunchbase&amp;rdquo;} at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unionsquareventures.com/&#34; title=&#34;Union Square Ventures&#34;&gt;Union Square Ventures&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} point to some very strong parallels to the content in some of the pieces in the Open Source Business Review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Union Square Ventures and a new kind of Venture Capital firm.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/union-square-ventures-and-a-new-kind-of-venture-capital-firm./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 05:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/union-square-ventures-and-a-new-kind-of-venture-capital-firm./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://unionsquareventures.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://img.skitch.com/20080924-q9dcb27qeu1bnpid73cmqeei7m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Union Square Ventures&#34;&gt;{.alignright decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;162&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;158&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nytimes.com/&#34; title=&#34;The New York Times&#34;&gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://unionsquareventures.com&#34;&gt;Union Square Ventures&lt;/a&gt; (USV) entitled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/09/22/technology/22venture.html?_r=1&amp;amp;oref=slogin&amp;amp;partner=rssnyt&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&#34;&gt;A New Kind Of Venture Capital Firm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; is an interesting read and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see the media beginning to pick up on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following USV for a whlie now and actually interviewed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.unionsquareventures.com/team/&#34;&gt;Brad Burnham&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for a session at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki&#34;&gt;Open Everything Retreat&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki/Agenda/Investing_in_Open&#34;&gt;Investing in Open&lt;/a&gt;. They seem to have a knack for investing in webtech ventures like &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34; title=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wesabe.com&#34; title=&#34;Wesabe&#34;&gt;Wesabe&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} that have models that can be deeply disruptive to the systems they are taking on and where the question of how they are going to make money from them is far from answered. And now they&amp;rsquo;re turning more of their attention to conventionally &amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo; issues including education and the environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People, this is the front desk – It’s time to WAKE UP!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/people-this-is-the-front-desk-its-time-to-wake-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 14:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/people-this-is-the-front-desk-its-time-to-wake-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
::: {.zemanta-img .zemanta-action-click}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34; style=&#34;width: 109px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Windup_alarm_clock.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/46/Windup_alarm_clock.jpg/202px-Windup_alarm_clock.jpg&#34; title=&#34;alarm clock, bought from IKEA&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;109&#34; height=&#34;94&#34; alt=&#34;alarm clock, bought from IKEA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Image via Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
:::
&lt;p&gt;The chaos of the financial markets is a major break in conventional structures and systems of our society. The intensity of it along side the growing crises in energy, food, and water coupled and the associated geo-political instability is really shaking things up. Oh, and mother nature is giving it&amp;rsquo;s own share of kicks amounting to what I hope is one big wakeup call.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A survey on the value of LinkedIn and Facebook to organizations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-survey-on-the-value-of-linkedin-and-facebook-to-organizations./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 04:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-survey-on-the-value-of-linkedin-and-facebook-to-organizations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable: cc-by-nc-ca Duncan Work --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off the cuff, I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about building a &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_capital&#34; title=&#34;Social capital&#34;&gt;social capital&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;wikipedia&amp;rdquo;} supercharger&amp;rsquo; over the past few months. It&amp;rsquo;s actually something that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working more deeply with &lt;a href=&#34;http://100trillion.wordpress.com/about/&#34;&gt;Duncan Work&lt;/a&gt; (DW), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/profile?viewProfile=&amp;amp;key=8445579&amp;amp;fromSearch=0&amp;amp;sik=1221260686175&amp;amp;split_page=1&amp;amp;authToken=LFNm&amp;amp;authType=NAME_SEARCH&amp;amp;goback=.nrp_1_1221260686175&#34;&gt;Duncan Holmes&lt;/a&gt; and few others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well DW has launched a simple survey to start capturing some experiences around using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/&#34; title=&#34;LinkedIn&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/&#34; title=&#34;Facebook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;{.zem_slink rel=&amp;ldquo;homepage&amp;rdquo;} in organizations. Needless to say we&amp;rsquo;d be very interested in how you use them. If you&amp;rsquo;re up for taking 5 minutes &amp;ndash; you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s.aspx?sm=YmPRsxc3TTlT2Vqq7zhrwQ_3d_3d&#34;&gt;take the survey here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Birth” and BOLD in Canada!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/birth-and-bold-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 15:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/birth-and-bold-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Birth is the most human and universal experience. We, as humans, are at our most powerful and our most vulnerable. It is the most natural process and a major life moment for both baby and mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow though, in our society we have institutionalized birth and made it something impersonal. We are fortunate to have all the technology and knowledge we have that can helps us deal with things that go awry &amp;ndash; but why is it that we start out treating pregnancy and birth as something that has &amp;lsquo;gone awry&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on OpenEverything: the rereat, the movement, and the meaning.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reflecting-on-openeverything-the-rereat-the-movement-and-the-meaning./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 20:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reflecting-on-openeverything-the-rereat-the-movement-and-the-meaning./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34; style=&#34;width: 192px&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3287/2839950029_267c57ae9c_m.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3287/2839950029_267c57ae9c_m.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The view at Hollyhock&#34; decoding=&#34;async&#34; width=&#34;192&#34; height=&#34;144&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Reflections at Hollyhock&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a week since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki&#34;&gt;OpenEverything retreat&lt;/a&gt; and the reverberations continue. Heading into it, not having any roots in the open-source community, I was technically the biggest noob on the convening team. At the same time, what drew me into the meme and the event was a sense that something bigger was going on and that that something was rooted in a set of ideals and a drive for the practical that resonated with my core and my life experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Open – Investing and Organizations</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/exploring-open-investing-and-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/exploring-open-investing-and-organizations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Well the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki&#34;&gt;OpenEverything Retreat&lt;/a&gt; turned out to be great event with over 30 participants and some great output. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki/Agenda/Investing_in_Open&#34;&gt;Investing in Open Session&lt;/a&gt; brought together Helen King from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shuttleworthfoundation.org&#34;&gt;Shuttleworth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}, Joel Solomon from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.renewalpartners.com&#34;&gt;Renewal Partners&lt;/a&gt;, and Paul Biondich from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmrs.org&#34;&gt;OpenMRS&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}. For the highlights check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Retreat_wiki/Agenda/Investing_in_Open&#34;&gt;notes from the session&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} and for those who want to dig a little deeper and contribute to the conversation there&amp;rsquo;s now a &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Mapping_Open/Explorations/Investing_and_Open&#34;&gt;open exploration on Investing and Open&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Mapping_Open&#34;&gt;Mapping Open&lt;/a&gt; section of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/&#34;&gt;OpenEverything wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The influence of open in venturing.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-influence-of-open-in-venturing./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-influence-of-open-in-venturing./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
So what does &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; mean for &amp;lsquo;venturing&amp;rsquo; and venturing on &amp;rsquo;the frontiers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From some prior &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/01/definitive-definitions-of-venturing.html&#34;&gt;definitions&lt;/a&gt;, venturing is process of creating and evolving a venture, where a venture is an agreement among people to do things in service of a purpose and according to a set of values. More simply it&amp;rsquo;s about the process of organizing resources (social, financial, and human capital) toward realizing a certain intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; really is about &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post75&#34;&gt;a new mode of organization&lt;/a&gt;, then it is central to the process of venturing. It will inevitably impact every venture, the leadership and culture required, and the way in which we go about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The point of ‘open’ – a new mode of organization.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-point-of-open-a-new-mode-of-organization./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-point-of-open-a-new-mode-of-organization./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
In working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.net/&#34;&gt;Open Everything&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling to come up with why it matters and what it means to the common person. For people in the open source community or other fields where &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; is a already at play they don&amp;rsquo;t tend to ask this question but if we are to &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; the open meme, we certainly need to be able to answer it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s how I answer it now. (Ad-lib [seesmic video answer below]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;})&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A crack in the dam – opening a new domain.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-crack-in-the-dam-opening-a-new-domain./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-crack-in-the-dam-opening-a-new-domain./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jef_safi/225426814/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/88/225426814_902dff2512_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jef_safi/225426814/&#34;&gt;Rhizoming the plane of emergence 2.0 . .&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/jef_safi/&#34;&gt;jεƒ saƒı&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been in the works for awhile and I now think we&amp;rsquo;re really starting to make a connection between web tech (2.0+), venture investing, social innovation. That connection is going to unleash some tremendous innovations and a surge in the activity directly working on the challenges facing our civilization. It feels like the emergence of a new domain that will take some very different approaches to change and influencing the course of civilization. It seems inspired by open source, technology innovation, financial risk taking, a venturing culture, and now a deepening and deeply felt realization that there are more important tasks to tend to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An open quote from Michael Edwards</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/an-open-quote-from-michael-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/an-open-quote-from-michael-edwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&#34;font-family: arial; font-weight: normal; font-style: italic;font-size:78%;&#34; id=&#34;cross-posted-from-my-tumblog&#34;&gt;[Cross posted from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;tumblog&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/39078854/open-more-radical-innovations-in-ownership-and&#34;&gt;Open: &amp;ldquo;more radical innovations in ownership and production that change the basis on which markets currently work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the conclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://justanotheremperor.org&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just Another Emperor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Edwards, he poses the above quote which I think is a great description of what &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; is actually playing at. Full context here: &amp;ldquo;Philanthrocapitalism offers one way of increasing the social value of the market, but there are other routes that could offer equal or better results in changing the way the economic surplus is produced, distributed and used: the traditional route that uses external pressure, taxation and regulation; the philanthrocapitalist route that changes internal incentives and gives a little more back through foundations and corporate social repsonsibility; and the more radical innovations in ownership and production that change the basis in which markets work. We don&amp;rsquo;t know which of these routes carries the greatest long term potential, though all of them rely on civil society as a vehicle for innovation, accountability, influence and modified consumption, and especially for getting us from reformist to transformational solutions.&amp;rdquo;
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benevolent dictators in the open movement</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/benevolent-dictators-in-the-open-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/benevolent-dictators-in-the-open-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SFkZZoVM3KI/AAAAAAAAAC4/kfsjLRe1l40/s1600-h/254908846_c8a5982675_m.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SFkZZoVM3KI/AAAAAAAAAC4/kfsjLRe1l40/s320/254908846_c8a5982675_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5213225971771825314 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;quot;}One of the interesting things coming out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/06/open-everything-toronto-reflection.html&#34;&gt;OPEN everything (Toronto)&lt;/a&gt; was the idea that open projects are driven by what we were calling &amp;lsquo;benevolent dictators&amp;rsquo;. That phrase, while abrasive to some, seems to be resonating in a number of different conversations that I and others are having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it seems to do is counter the notion that open is a touchy-[feely]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}, everyone has to agree, happy place where everyone gets along. At the same time it reinforces the important and evolving role of leadership. What I&amp;rsquo;m starting to try and tease out is what are the qualities of open leadership that we&amp;rsquo;re really getting at? And which of those are core values &amp;ndash; and which are situational reactions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPEN everything (Toronto) Reflection</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/open-everything-toronto-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 19:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/open-everything-toronto-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SEmdcAjmpxI/AAAAAAAAACw/1X05Ikts02I/s1600-h/OpenEverythingLogo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SEmdcAjmpxI/AAAAAAAAACw/1X05Ikts02I/s320/OpenEverythingLogo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5208867548541921042 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;quot;}The first half-day &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.net/&#34;&gt;OPEN everything&lt;/a&gt; event happened in Toronto at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialinnovation.ca/&#34;&gt;Centre for Social&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialinnovation.ca/&#34;&gt;Innovation&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday and was a great start to what&amp;rsquo;s going to be a very interesting series. &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonspace.typepad.com/about.html&#34;&gt;Mark Surman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; the mastermind of the series &amp;ndash; opened the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.wik.is/Toronto&#34;&gt;agenda&lt;/a&gt; and launched the group into an exploration of what &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; is and what are the underlying principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenEverything opens today!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-opens-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-opens-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Well, it was only a few months ago when &lt;a href=&#34;http://communicopia.net/who-we-are/our-team/jason-mogus&#34;&gt;Jason [Mogus]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonspace.typepad.com/about.html&#34;&gt;Mark [Surman]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt; and I chatted on this concept of the event series that is now underway. It started as an exploration as to a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://webofchange.com&#34;&gt;Web Of Change&lt;/a&gt; event at Hollyhock this year and Mark has taken it to what is going to be an amazing series that is going to push our thinking and the thinking of the &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; community even further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some related links – adding on to another conversation.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/some-related-links-adding-on-to-another-conversation./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/some-related-links-adding-on-to-another-conversation./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I commented on Fred Wilson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.blogs.com/a_vc/2008/05/looking-forward.html&#34;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/a&gt; post yesterday and he [reblogged]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} a part of my comment in his [tumblog]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} &lt;a href=&#34;http://fredwilson.vc/post/34956572#disqus_thread&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. [Tt&amp;rsquo;s]{#SPELLING_ERROR_2 .blsp-spelling-error} been generating a few emails to me so for those that are interested, here are a few other links that follow that theme&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; A few of us are convening an event that is digging deeper into that mindset that riffs off open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.net&#34;&gt;[openeverything]{#SPELLING_ERROR_3 .blsp-spelling-error}.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; [Ervin]{#SPELLING_ERROR_4 .blsp-spelling-error} [Laszlo&amp;rsquo;s]{#SPELLING_ERROR_5 .blsp-spelling-error} &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or.html&#34;&gt;[Macroshift]{#SPELLING_ERROR_6 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; a book about the evolution of civilization and the interplay of technology and mindsets (my highlights and links to the book &amp;ndash; additional post &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/11/rest-of-macroshift.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; A post of mine on this phase we are in that I&amp;rsquo;m calling &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/05/great-remix.html&#34;&gt;the Great Remix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Additional posts &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/05/doing-differently-in-great-remix.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/11/rest-of-macroshift.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/higlights-from-of-enterprise-viable.html&#34;&gt;Stafford Beer&amp;rsquo;s work&lt;/a&gt; on information design of systems in an organizational context (my highlights and links to his book and work)
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forces at play in the The Great Remix</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/forces-at-play-in-the-the-great-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/forces-at-play-in-the-the-great-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::::: entry-content
The final piece from this work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post65&#34;&gt;The Great Remix&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post66&#34;&gt;also&lt;/a&gt;) are a couple of presentations that explore the forces at play. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to add annotated detail but here they are nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Summary]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold; font-size: 130%;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;margin-bottom:5px&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-great-remix-presentation-summary&#34; title=&#34;The Great Remix Presentation Summary&#34;&gt;The Great Remix Presentation Summary&lt;/a&gt;{target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt;{target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}&lt;/strong&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {#__ss_396903 style=&amp;ldquo;width: 425px; text-align: left;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Detail]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold; font-size: 130%;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;margin-bottom:5px&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-great-remix-presentation-detail&#34; title=&#34;The Great Remix Presentation Detail&#34;&gt;The Great Remix Presentation Detail&lt;/a&gt;{target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt;{target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}&lt;/strong&gt;
:::
::::::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing differently in the Great Remix</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/doing-differently-in-the-great-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/doing-differently-in-the-great-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The one other piece that I&amp;rsquo;ll share from my exploration into &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post65&#34;&gt;the Great Remix&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post67&#34;&gt;also&lt;/a&gt;), is a part about how I see doing happening differently as we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following four areas now describe how doing is different in the context of the Great Remix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Employ Systems Dynamics]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
[ (From conductor to mix master)]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-style: italic;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
As the systems of our civilization demonstrate instability and failure more frequently, openings are created for previously unexpected initiatives to emerge. We can&amp;rsquo;t know when or how but rather must work to condition the emergence of those initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Remix</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-great-remix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-great-remix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Part of my silence over the last few months has been from some deep-digging I was doing in an engagement with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://marsdd.com/MaRS-Services/Business-Advisory-Services/Social-Innovation.html&#34;&gt;Social Innovation group at MaRS&lt;/a&gt; and with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialinnovation.ca/&#34;&gt;Centre for Social Innovation&lt;/a&gt;. One of the great things about the engagement was an opportunity to push deeper into what&amp;rsquo;s underneath social innovation, social entrepreneurship and social enterprise. What&amp;rsquo;s come from that is seeping into most everything I&amp;rsquo;m doing right now &amp;ndash; and so it&amp;rsquo;s about time I get back to posting what I&amp;rsquo;ve been discovering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Tech Training – June 22-24, 2008</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-tech-training-june-22-24-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-tech-training-june-22-24-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/socialtechtraining&#34; title=&#34;SocialTech Training&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SocialTech Training&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://webofchange.com/sites/webofchange.com/files/images/stt_badge5.gif&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/socialtechtraining&#34;&gt;Social Tech Training&lt;/a&gt; is happening this June in Toronto.  Here&amp;rsquo;s the link and a quick blurb.  Check-it out and sign-up if it catches your eye. Coming from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webofchange.com&#34;&gt;Web of Change&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/&#34;&gt;MaRS&lt;/a&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s bound to be an excellent event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::::: {}
::: {}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {}
No one working in social change these days can afford to ignore the opportunities offered by the web. Most organizations get stuck, though, on &amp;ldquo;How do we do it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Where do we start?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Who can help us?&amp;rdquo; Interest in high, but the talent pool of people equipped to understand, prioritize, and implement these tools and ideas remains limited.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Bets n’ chips” – Implications for investors on the frontiers.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/bets-n-chips-implications-for-investors-on-the-frontiers./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/bets-n-chips-implications-for-investors-on-the-frontiers./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seem to be two types of bets that investors make when doing a deal. A bet on the team. A bet on the plan. The closer to the frontiers (early stages and deep change) the greater the emphasis is on the team. And rightly so. We all know that plans don&amp;rsquo;t last on the frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Gettin’ lucky” – implications for ventures on the frontiers.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-lucky-implications-for-ventures-on-the-frontiers./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-lucky-implications-for-ventures-on-the-frontiers./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the gist of this image &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/02/venturing-on-frontiers-simple-guide.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Now I&amp;rsquo;m turning to the implications for venturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply the essence of venturing is a process. A process of creating spaces for things to happen (some call it &amp;rsquo;luck&amp;rsquo;). The simpler and more accessible the space, the easier it is to get people engaged and get things done (some would say &amp;rsquo;the luckier you get&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the Frontiers – A simple guide.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venturing on the frontiers is about the early stages of taking on big challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s a space where conventional models to planning and management prove ineffective. It&amp;rsquo;s the place where entrepeneurs trust their &amp;lsquo;gut&amp;rsquo; and face the challenges with an unrelenting push forward. And it&amp;rsquo;s the place from which the greatest change can come about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing and venture investing on the frontiers – in simple terms.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-venture-investing-on-the-frontiers-in-simple-terms./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-venture-investing-on-the-frontiers-in-simple-terms./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked a few times about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on in simple terms. Not always easy for me &amp;ndash; but here goes top-of-mind while riding the train&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[My focus is on venturing and venture investing &amp;lsquo;on the frontiers&amp;rsquo;. ]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venturing is about organizing and directing resources toward a purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venture investing is about improving the capacity of ventures to achieve their purpose (or certain milestones along the way)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;on the frontiers&amp;rsquo; means the places where conventional ways of doing things are least effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work is focused on being able to systematically improve ventures and venture investors operating on the frontiers. My belief is that by focusing here, practices can be developed and demonstrated that will themselves become conventional in time and thereby move &amp;rsquo;the frontiers&amp;rsquo; greatly increasing our society&amp;rsquo;s ability and capacity to take on our civilization&amp;rsquo;s greatest challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Social’-lingo</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-lingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Many things have been picking up the &amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo; modifier lately. Here are some of the ones I&amp;rsquo;m encountering and what I think they mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the modifier [&amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo;]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modifies the following word to the focus of serving a social (and/or environmental) benefit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[tech]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technology employed for social benefit (most commonly digital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[change]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concerned generally with societal change and how it happens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[innovation]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;innovations and the process of innovating solutions that deliver or enable social change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[venture]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘evil’ in exchanges.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-evil-in-exchanges./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-evil-in-exchanges./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Exchanges are a hot topic in the social capital markets. They are appealing in the sense of the efficiency they promise. Efficiency is good &amp;ndash; and it also has a dark side. This dark-side, which I&amp;rsquo;m considering the &amp;lsquo;inherent evil&amp;rsquo; in exchanges, is their tendency to disconnect/dissociate the &amp;lsquo;buyer&amp;rsquo; from the &amp;lsquo;seller&amp;rsquo;. It comes out in things like the sub-prime mess and rogue traders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we get the benefits of this &amp;lsquo;masterpiece&amp;rsquo; of capitalism?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This biggering is buggering… a call for a new vision of ‘prosperity’.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/this-biggering-is-buggering-a-call-for-a-new-vision-of-prosperity./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/this-biggering-is-buggering-a-call-for-a-new-vision-of-prosperity./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I attended a session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sustainableprosperity.ca/&#34;&gt;Sustainable Prosperity&lt;/a&gt; last week and was left with a pretty big realization that evolved for me into what blurted out in a strategy session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windfallcentre.ca/&#34;&gt;Windfall Ecology Centre&lt;/a&gt; on Friday as..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This [BIGGERING]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} is buggering&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is inspired by Dr. Seuss&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Lorax-Classic-Seuss-Dr/dp/0394823370/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1201558467&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The [Lorax]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error}&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, (see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/24907301&#34;&gt;specific quotes here&lt;/a&gt;), but it also refers to a growing realization that the thing that economy is based on &amp;ndash; continuously increasing consumption &amp;ndash; is reaching a breaking point. To be clear, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a recession inspired &amp;lsquo;people aren&amp;rsquo;t going to consume as much anymore&amp;rsquo; statement, it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;lsquo;if people consume anywhere near what we&amp;rsquo;re consuming we&amp;rsquo;re all screwed&amp;rsquo; statement. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.storyofstuff.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Story of Stuff&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freerangemedia.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Free Range Media&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tides.org/&#34;&gt;Tides Foundation&lt;/a&gt; makes a simple and decent case for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The definitive definitions of venturing!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
One of the surprising things that I came out of my latest exploration into the frontiers of venturing and venture investing is a set of definitions. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not one that likes to debate definitions ad infinitum but I found I needed to clarify things to be able to have meaningful conversations going forward. So here, is what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with&amp;hellip; for now (I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this definitions as the evolve so feel free to check-back or link here for reference).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd sourcing in venturing</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/crowd-sourcing-in-venturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/crowd-sourcing-in-venturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Just saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidcrow.ca/article/1812/crowd-powered-capital&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; tipping me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cambrianhouse.com/vencorps/&#34;&gt;VenCorps&lt;/a&gt; which seems to be a venture fund using &amp;lsquo;crowd sourcing&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be interested to see how it goes and expect they will do well by essentially &amp;lsquo;amping up the network&amp;rsquo;. My guess is that they will be better at dealing with ambiguity (related to progressing along stage of development) in ventures but I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see if it will help them deal with complexity (related to depth of systemic change). The thing that gives me a sense that they won&amp;rsquo;t be as effective here is the military style they are coming out with. That to me indicates a very linear, command and control approach which is not effective in dealing with complexity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giddy-up: getting better on the frontier.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Coming out of this first inquiry I&amp;rsquo;m left with new definitions for venture, venturing, and venturer and also a simplistic grouping that the process of venturing essentially requires agreement, action, and governance. It is important to note that these are a set of observations and interpretations that will continue to be evolved in practice. As such they represent a starting point for a concerted effort to &amp;lsquo;get better at venturing and investing on the frontiers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want, need, and enough.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/want-need-and-enough./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/want-need-and-enough./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A brief twitter conversation with Tom at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.givemeaning.com&#34;&gt;www.givemeaning.com&lt;/a&gt; on this subject had me feeling limited by the 140 character twitter limit&amp;hellip; so here goes a quick mobile post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been conscious of the impact and role of consumption in our society for a while but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.storyofstuff.com&#34;&gt;www.storyofstuff.com&lt;/a&gt; and the movie Manufactured Landscapes from Mongrel Media have had me thinking a bit deeper lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think &#39;giving&#39; has largely becoming another form of buying. Certainly giving has very little to do with need &amp;ndash; unless ofcourse you turn to things like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.givemeaning.com&#34;&gt;www.givemeaning.com&lt;/a&gt; :-). And the concept of enough is an abstract thing that is a personal, individual assessment of their own fulfillment of wants. And wants are fueled by cosumption. The more people shop and buy, the more they are exposed to things they could have and so are encouraged to have new wants. Green consumerism fits right into that. I&#39;m all for efficiency and recycling but those shouldn&#39;t encourage further consumption beyond replacement of what is no longer working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gettin’ it goin’ without goin’ under: cohesion and incipient instability.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
With requisite attention being held a natural propulsion will emerge.  The act of managing and nurturing that propulsion is attended to with a focus on cohesion and being proactively aware of the emergence of incipient instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts are addressed in depth in Stafford Beer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;viable system model&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/higlights-from-of-enterprise-viable.html&#34;&gt;my reflections here&lt;/a&gt; on reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Enterprise-Classic-Beer/dp/0471948373/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1199076860&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Heart of Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;) and are really about holding the tension between future (vision), and here and now (operations) [see last post for &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/12/venturing-on-frontier-requisite.html&#34;&gt;more on requisite attention&lt;/a&gt;]. Cohesion has a lot to do with articulating purpose as so well described by[ ]{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration: underline;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_C._Collins&#34;&gt;Collins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_Porras&#34;&gt;Porras&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://harvardbusinessonline.hbsp.harvard.edu/b02/en/common/item_detail.jhtml?id=410X&amp;amp;referral=2340&#34;&gt;Building Your Company&amp;rsquo;s Vision&lt;/a&gt;. And incipient instability is about monitoring trends in financials, plan performance, and relationship status (after all, ventures are systems, concentrated bundles of relationships), and then spotting changes that indicate that something is becoming instable in a way that could harm the cohesion of the system as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the frontier: requisite attention</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Venturing on the frontiers requires distinctly holding attention on two discrete aspects of any venture:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Productive, iterative, exploration of the complexity dynamic&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Core venture viability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple to say but in practice, venturers who aren&amp;rsquo;t stuck in perpetual analysis and thought, are pulled toward focusing on linear, or hopefully exponential, growth of the most promising aspect at hand particularly after attracting professional investment capital. Stop thinking and just do it right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venture investing shake-up? Really?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venture-investing-shake-up-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 22:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venture-investing-shake-up-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
An interesting article about a new way of doing deals &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile2.wsj.com/beta2/htmlsite/html_article.php?id=1&amp;amp;CALL_URL=http://online.wsj.com/article/SB119889558568757053.html&#34;&gt;http://mobile2.wsj.com/beta2/htmlsite/html_article.php?id=1&amp;amp;CALL_URL=http://online.wsj.com/article/SB119889558568757053.html&lt;/a&gt; (thanks to Fred @ USV &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.blogs.com&#34;&gt;http://avc.blogs.com&lt;/a&gt; for the pointer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this article really seems to be dancing around is value of relationships in finding and doing deals and in venture success. What also comes is the conventional approach of being hands-off if you are going in early and also the power of being lean/lightweight in early-stage venturing. I&#39;m in the midst of doing a series of posts from my lastest conversations on the frontiers of venturing and this fits&amp;hellip; and it&#39;s also a good reminder of how little really is changing on the frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics of the frontier: complex ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The frontiers of venturing are the places where conventional venturing and planning approaches become least effective. It is the effective limit of conventional approaches to venturing that define the edge of the frontier with the deepest depths of the frontier being the pre-concept stage of a systemically focused venture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831.jpg?v=0&#34; title=&#34;Frontiers of venturing&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 10px 10px 0pt 0pt; float: left; width: 286px; height: 265px;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
Conventional approaches loose effectiveness the earlier a venture is in the development phase because of increasing ambiguity.  The less that is known the harder it is to do linear modeling and planning.  Choices made continually reduce ambiguity as the venture moves along the development and into the realm where conventional planning approaches can be effectively used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the frontiers – Inquiry #1wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-inquiry-%231wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-inquiry-%231wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A little over a year-ago I began considering &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post3&#34;&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s next in my journey&lt;/a&gt; and exactly 3 months ago I &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post29&#34;&gt;initiated my first inquiry&lt;/a&gt; into what&amp;rsquo;s needed on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post40&#34;&gt;frontiers of venturing and venture investing&lt;/a&gt;. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a linear journey of course, with a good deal of my attention going towards getting &lt;a href=&#34;http://causeway.socialfinance.ca/&#34;&gt;Causeway&lt;/a&gt; going over the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that was ongoing, I had about a dozen conversations over November and December with some extraordinary social venture investors and funds in North America (including &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.renewalpartners.com/&#34;&gt;Renewal Partners&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialcapitalpartners.com/&#34;&gt;Social Capital Partners&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wkkf.org/default.aspx?LanguageID=0&#34;&gt;Kellogg Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rsfsocialfinance.org/&#34;&gt;RSF Social Finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodcap.net/&#34;&gt;Good Capital&lt;/a&gt; and others). To all of you I am tremendously grateful for the generosity of your time, the candor with which you shared your experiences and the enthusiasm with which you&amp;rsquo;ve approached this exploration. Each conversation integrated into my own experiences and readings, and into every other conversation. What has emerged for me is a point of summary from which I feel ready to attempt some active experiments into how do we get better on the frontiers as venturers and venture investors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social blogging</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
[[]{#formatbar_CreateLink .on onmousedown=&amp;ldquo;CheckFormatting(event);FormatbarButton(&amp;lsquo;richeditorframe&amp;rsquo;, this, 8);ButtonMouseDown(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseout=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOff(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseover=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOn(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseup=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;Link&amp;rdquo;}]{#formatbar_Buttons style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo;}[[]{#formatbar_CreateLink .on .down onmousedown=&amp;ldquo;CheckFormatting(event);FormatbarButton(&amp;lsquo;richeditorframe&amp;rsquo;, this, 8);ButtonMouseDown(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseout=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOff(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseover=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOn(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseup=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;Link&amp;rdquo;}]{#formatbar_Buttons style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;quot;}Fred Wilson at &lt;a href=&#34;www.unionsquareventures.com&#34;&gt;USV&lt;/a&gt; had &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.blogs.com/a_vc/2007/12/social-blogging.html&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; exploring the differences in &lt;a href=&#34;www.twitter.com&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; from other things like blogs and social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure there are a lot of people reading this who think &amp;ldquo;how is this different than blogging?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d like to suggest that everyone try this&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring incipient instability</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/measuring-incipient-instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/measuring-incipient-instability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about what it is that really needs to be tracked in early-stage and transformative ventures. There certainly is the simple dynamic of financial viability and then there is the concept of productive, iterative exploration in the area of complex ambiguity I raised in an earlier post. I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging into what the measures are that actually help indicate the emergence of potential instability &amp;ndash; before it&amp;rsquo;s actually happened. That&amp;rsquo;s the trick because learning that ap has exceeded cash + ar at the next board meeting isn&amp;rsquo;t very helpful. And that&amp;rsquo;s not such a rare scenario &amp;ndash; e.g. customer holding 80% or your ar is suddenly unable to pay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complex ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/complex-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/complex-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
In my last post I intoduced &amp;lsquo;complex ambiguity&amp;rsquo; as the stuff in venturing that entrepreneurs are really trying to figure out &amp;mdash; where no-one &amp;lsquo;knows&amp;rsquo; the answer. The deeper the change and the earlier the stage the greater the complexity and the ambiguity. My earlier tumbls &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/20306132&#34;&gt;about pentagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/20308643&#34;&gt;that one designer&lt;/a&gt; have tweaked me that it&amp;rsquo;s akin to the creative process. Like designing a logo. Except that venturing can be a pereptual series of logos for something that itself is somewhat ambiguous and continuinally evolving. That&amp;rsquo;s complex ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing and investing on the frontiers: Intial observations…</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-investing-on-the-frontiers-intial-observations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-investing-on-the-frontiers-intial-observations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Having been doing nothing but early-stage venturing from all sides of the table for more than a decade I decided to start a series of conversations to explore what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831.jpg?v=0&#34;&gt;{.reflect decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; onload=&amp;ldquo;show_notes_initially();&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;width: 373px; height: 347px;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this initial set of conversations, primarily with investors working on &amp;rsquo;the frontier&amp;rsquo; (social change and social tech) here are some of my initial observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1. Being on the frontier increases &amp;ldquo;complex ambiguity&amp;rdquo;]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;} (we don&amp;rsquo;t really know what we are doing, and if we think we do it&amp;rsquo;s probably a false sense of security)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rest of the macroshift.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-rest-of-the-macroshift./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-rest-of-the-macroshift./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Continuing on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or.html&#34;&gt;previous macroshift post&lt;/a&gt;, here are my reflections from the remainder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Macroshift-Navigating-Transformation-Sustainable-World/dp/1576751635/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-0269927-3836077?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1193681423&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Macroshift&lt;/a&gt;{bluekey=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; bluelink=&amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me the rest of the book was a lighter read with some simple observations relating to the mindset shift that is called for and clearly already underway. Here are a couple of framing quotes to set the stage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the past, a more adapted civilization evolved over several generations; the rythym of change was relatively slow. This is no longer the case. The critical period for change today is compressed within the lifetime of a single generation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macroshift (Ervin Laszlo) — Doomsday or Breakthrough?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or-breakthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or-breakthrough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m only through the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Macroshift-Navigating-Transformation-Sustainable-World/dp/1576751635/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-0269927-3836077?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1193681423&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Macroshift&lt;/a&gt;, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d better post these snippets before I get caught-up in the flow of the week.  I came across this through a client who pointed to this as the best description of what their work is responding to.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more&amp;hellip; and know a few others that will feel the same way&amp;hellip; and am hoping more people will join those ranks. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The early days of the Internet – an original CBC news story.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-early-days-of-the-internet-an-original-cbc-news-story./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2007 16:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-early-days-of-the-internet-an-original-cbc-news-story./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I just caught this in &lt;a href=&#34;http://beth.typepad.com/beths_blog/2007/10/this-new-thing-.html&#34;&gt;Beth&amp;rsquo;s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow&amp;hellip; how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come, in such short time, and yet how relevant the social observations remain today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogged with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flock.com/blogged-with-flock&#34; title=&#34;Flock&#34;&gt;Flock&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_new&amp;quot;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higlights from “Heart of Enterprise” — the Viable System Model</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/higlights-from-heart-of-enterprise-the-viable-system-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/higlights-from-heart-of-enterprise-the-viable-system-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
[&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working my way through this tome for a few weeks and have had a number of conversations around it. It&amp;rsquo;s by far the most valuable piece of work I&amp;rsquo;ve ever encountered on organizational design &amp;mdash; and for me a critical model in ventures that are on the venturing frontier (early concept stage and/or systemic co-creation &amp;mdash; see graph below).]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-size:100%;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/60514480@N00/1748323488/&#34; title=&#34;Efficacy of venturing and investing models and practices&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Efficacy of venturing and investing models and practices&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awaiting the accounting revolution.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/awaiting-the-accounting-revolution./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 01:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/awaiting-the-accounting-revolution./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been twittering my frustrations today.  I have a fairly simple financial situation and have 2 companies that I process both Shawna&amp;rsquo;s and my work through.  There&amp;rsquo;s nothing complex with either of them so I&amp;rsquo;ve been filing the taxes and handling the bookkeeping myself since the beginning except for a short stint where I outsourced the annual filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My frustration is that doing it myself is harder than it should be. Bookkeeping/accounting software is far more cumbersome and antequated than it should be, and it costs too much for things that should be free (tax table updates and payroll functionality).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A good point – enough with the debate on climate change.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-good-point-enough-with-the-debate-on-climate-change./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-good-point-enough-with-the-debate-on-climate-change./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
This is a nice argument for stopping the debate on climate change and getting on with it.  I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in the only answer to be policy change but it is an important one.  The basic argument is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; we can&amp;rsquo;t know for certain whether or not we are impacting climate change or what will happen&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; we can only choose whether or not we are going to do something about it&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; that choice really comes down to an assessment of the risk in acting or not&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; if we act, worst case is economic downturn&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; if we don&amp;rsquo;t act, worst case is economic downturn PLUS other global catashrophies&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dress code? Ugghhh…</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/dress-code-ugghhh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/dress-code-ugghhh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
As time goes on I increasingly consider clothing first and foremost about function and comfort. For me this means jeans as my primary leg wear and then anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t need ironing for my tops. And for footwear it&amp;rsquo;s either my Crocs or Blundstones for sheer practicality. For some client work though, I still feel the need to at least put on a &amp;lsquo;dress-shirt&amp;rsquo; and some other pants.  On rare occasion &amp;ndash; like the social finance forum &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll break-out a suit. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Cotton</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/black-cotton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2007 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/black-cotton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve long know a lot about the coffee industry and had heard snippets of what&amp;rsquo;s going on in cotton too&amp;hellip; but this sure is a wakeup call.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing forward.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-forward./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-forward./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
So now with intellectual models for aligning a venture around a purposeful response to a deep calling, and for designing a viable organizational system it begs the question &amp;ndash; now what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment. Investment of capital&amp;hellip; intellectual, social, and financial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ideal clean slate this might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify a calling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gather a group of diverse though leaders and community members to explore/deepen the calling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conduct an &amp;rsquo;externalities analysis&#39;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reconvene a modified group to:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uncover a responsive purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concieve of a theory of change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and anchor it with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BHAG_%28Goal%29&#34;&gt;Big Hairy Audacious Goal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conduct an &amp;lsquo;internalities analysis&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design the viable system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reconvene a modified group to:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;craft strategic directions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;establish near-term action plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this cannot be a rigidly linear/sequential process but rather is an iterative co-creative one. It is also a continual process of capital investment: intellectual, social, and financial&amp;hellip; done in an integrated co-creative style. And that&amp;rsquo;s what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/ignition-fund-i&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on now&lt;/a&gt;.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viable System Model – the second fulcrum.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/viable-system-model-the-second-fulcrum./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/viable-system-model-the-second-fulcrum./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The second fulcrum in [transformative]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} venturing is the way in which the venture is organized/organizes itself. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been introduced into something that has come closest to describing what it means to build a successful organization. And it&amp;rsquo;s not about outcomes or results &amp;ndash; those are simply that, outcomes &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s about the way in which it&amp;rsquo;s done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venture_capital&#34;&gt;Stafford Beer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s) &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;Viable Systems Model&lt;/a&gt;, or [VSM]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_%28abstract%29&#34; title=&#34;Model (abstract)&#34;&gt;model&lt;/a&gt; of the organisational structure of any viable or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autonomous&#34; title=&#34;Autonomous&#34;&gt;autonomous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System&#34; title=&#34;System&#34;&gt;system&lt;/a&gt;. A viable system is any system organised in such a way as to meet the demands of surviving in the changing environment. One of the prime features of systems that survive is that they are adaptable. The [VSM]{#SPELLING_ERROR_2 .blsp-spelling-error} expresses a model for a viable system, which is an abstracted cybernetic description that is applicable to any organisation that is a viable system and capable of autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venture Vortex</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venture-vortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venture-vortex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting management theories and practices that I found useful in venturing and found myself starting to organize them into a map. That map started painting a picture that has now become the Venture Vortex model.&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp3.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/RwG6yr2mwGI/AAAAAAAAABA/92ykxiy8rTU/s1600-h/Venture+Vortex.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp3.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/RwG6yr2mwGI/AAAAAAAAABA/92ykxiy8rTU/s400/Venture+Vortex.gif&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5116576031597576290 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s primary strength is in providing a platform to organize thinking around the process of building a venture and I am using it both as a design and a diagnostic tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twittering consiousness 2 (tracking)</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/twittering-consiousness-2-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/twittering-consiousness-2-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Twitter just announced the ability to track words in the entire &amp;lsquo;[twittersphere]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}&amp;rsquo;. I for example am now tracking:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; systemic&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; intervention&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; co-create&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; venture&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Canada&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Byron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when anyone does a post with any of those words in it I&amp;rsquo;ll see it. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me because I can in a way tap into a broad consciousness flow (comprised of small top-of-mind comments) to see what&amp;rsquo;s happening with these words. Will be interesting to see how this goes &amp;ndash; I imagine at lease I&amp;rsquo;ll find some interesting new people to follow &amp;ndash; and that so far has proven to be a good thing.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The two (or 3) fulcrums of transformative venturing.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-two-or-3-fulcrums-of-transformative-venturing./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-two-or-3-fulcrums-of-transformative-venturing./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A thought occured to me that there are in essence two fulcrums in the intentional creation of a transformative venture (a venture working on a systems-depth shift/consciousness change) &amp;ndash; and those are the purpose and the business system. And perhaps these two fulcrums interplay through another fulcrum &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BHAG_%28Goal%29&#34;&gt;BHAG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is coming to me as I&amp;rsquo;m exploring the connection between the Venture Vortex model and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stafford_Beer&#34;&gt;Stafford Beer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;Viable System Model&lt;/a&gt;. More posts on these later but this seems like it is starting to come together.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twittering consciousness</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/twittering-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/twittering-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/Igniter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a few months &amp;ndash; as well as facebook &amp;ndash; and Twitter is the one that is holding my interest in terms of what I perceive as an interesting connection to the movement of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People use it in different ways but what I find consistent is that I find myself feeling a deeper connection to the people I&amp;rsquo;m following. And this goes for my brother in Phoenix, a VC I&amp;rsquo;ve never met but that has similar interests, and a librarian that I simply found through Twitter because they live near me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A break in the silence – Ignition Fund I</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-break-in-the-silence-ignition-fund-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-break-in-the-silence-ignition-fund-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
It&amp;rsquo;s been over two months since my last blog and it seems what was holding me up was getting a first draft of my Ignition Fund I thinking out. Well at last, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/ignition-fund-i&#34;&gt;here it is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see where this goes &amp;ndash; as someone said to me yesterday it seems to be capturing my life&amp;rsquo;s experiences so far. Sure feels that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On with other posts&amp;hellip;
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The beauty of good online services — unfolding.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-beauty-of-good-online-services-unfolding./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-beauty-of-good-online-services-unfolding./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been actively trying different online services and tools lately, one of which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wesabe.com&#34;&gt;www.wesabe.com&lt;/a&gt;. It was a particularly interesting test for me as it deals with personal financial data (for most people one the most sensitive data streams) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long-time user of Microsoft Money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I found it interesting but it was an effort to use it. Well&amp;hellip; they just launched a firefox browser extension which makes my uploads even easier than they were with the version of Money I was using.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic interventions — the fun stuff!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/systemic-interventions-the-fun-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/systemic-interventions-the-fun-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve linked to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.developerdotstar.com/mag/articles/places_intervene_system.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; on the left, but can&amp;rsquo;t seem to say it enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donella Meadows&amp;rsquo; description of places to intervene in a system is the best guide I&amp;rsquo;ve come across for this stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily use it as a way to categorize the type or degree of systemic intervention an initiative is taking on but rather as a prompt to help me feel for the where an intervention may be most effective and what shifts may be prompted by the intervention being contemplated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts of systemic intervention.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/catalysts-of-systemic-intervention./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/catalysts-of-systemic-intervention./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work with some great folks that are doing/working on amazing regional transformations through a systems approach. It&amp;rsquo;s [occured]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} to me that they&amp;rsquo;re using two [seperate]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} catalysts in making that happen. One is using financial capital and the other community empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our current society, financial capital is one of the most powerful constructs in society and for now and always the empowerment or uprising of community is the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The tension of the two stories.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-tension-of-the-two-stories./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-tension-of-the-two-stories./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
It&amp;rsquo;s becoming more and more clear to me that our society is going through a major and accelerating transformation from the currently established &amp;rsquo;linear&amp;rsquo; mindset toward a &amp;lsquo;systems&amp;rsquo; mindset. There are countless ways to describe it but it is increasingly evident and felt particularly among those who are working on solutions to address the growing social and ecologcial threats our society is facing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tension of those two models colliding is palpable. The art of bringing them together is beautiful. The potential for it is limited and spontaneous. It&amp;rsquo;s not always possible and it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes unexpectedly possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seed venturing toward systemic interventions – deal funnel: screening, conditions, and structuring.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/seed-venturing-toward-systemic-interventions-deal-funnel-screening-conditions-and-structuring./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/seed-venturing-toward-systemic-interventions-deal-funnel-screening-conditions-and-structuring./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Seeding ventures focussed on systemic interventions needs to be come at with an approach that is grounded in systems thinking. Conventional wisdom in venture investment has come from theory and experiences often based in working with business systems that are working within and dependent on the current system itself. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that the earlier the stage of investment and the more oriented the venture is toward a systemic intervention the more &amp;lsquo;gut instinct&amp;rsquo; is used a guide to making investment decisions and supporting the growth and success of those ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Venturing Model</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-venturing-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-venturing-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to post on this for a while now. It&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot of my latest understanding of the venturing process. It&amp;rsquo;s early draft and the writing below is pretty much stream of consciousness but I&amp;rsquo;m being drawn to just get it out:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Ro8IMBZz5lI/AAAAAAAAAAw/KmGG5MgFhUc/s1600-h/iggy-ivm-v1a.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Ro8IMBZz5lI/AAAAAAAAAAw/KmGG5MgFhUc/s400/iggy-ivm-v1a.gif&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5084291506952726098 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re in an interesting point in history where there is a transition from a mindset based on seeking to understand the smallest components of things (reductionist thinking, command and control models, &amp;rsquo;the great clockwork&amp;rsquo;, world/problems as &amp;lsquo;complicated&amp;rsquo;) toward a mindset that looks at systems in terms of the relationships/context in order to understand them (systems, ecological, &amp;lsquo;complex&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online &gt; mobile/recovering &gt; present</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/online-mobile/recovering-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/online-mobile/recovering-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been actively putting myself online&amp;hellip; or rather updating my online presences and trying out the tools to manage my online connections lately and having been finding myself being hyper connected and active while I&amp;rsquo;m at my computer. While I&amp;rsquo;m working I&amp;rsquo;m usually listening to music, have a variety of online tools open (google reader, basecamp, slideshare, etc.) while at the same time doing email and working on docs/presentations. When I&amp;rsquo;m in that mode I can be hyper productive&amp;hellip; but sometimes, like an hour ago, my nervous system screams &amp;lsquo;stop&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavy load? Or not heavy enough?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/heavy-load-or-not-heavy-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 01:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/heavy-load-or-not-heavy-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I had my first chance to spend some time with Andres [Dussan]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} from [Ashoka]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} here in Canada. Just an introductory meeting from some mutual friends and it&amp;rsquo;s been a conversation that&amp;rsquo;s stuck with me a few days&amp;hellip; deeper than I originally realized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andres talked passionately about the power of media in shifting the cultural mindset to place where balance between people and the planet can re-emerge. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this conversation a number of times over the past year but something in it reminded me of the responsibility I have as white guy with upper-middle class roots, living in an affluent city within Canada. This is something that I was really first awakened to when I met my wife Shawna years ago but somehow since getting married, having our two kids and moving into a comfortable house with a big yard and lots of family support around I&amp;rsquo;ve conveniently put that responsibility aside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/emergence./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/emergence./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
After much prodding a picked up the book &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/books/item/books-978067931443/0679314431/Getting-to-Maybe-How-the-World-Is-Changed?ref=Search+Books%3a+%27getting+to+maybe%27&#34;&gt;Getting to Maybe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; and started reading it on the weekend. I have been pushing deeper into &amp;rsquo;the entrepreneurial approach&amp;rsquo; and working with the idea that it is more about the creating/holding the space for things to emerge. This morning I read the chapter called &amp;lsquo;Let It Find You&amp;rsquo; which is all about emergence. I am more convinced that in this element of entrepreneurship/social innovation is the &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; that can be amplified and applied to restoring balance among people and the planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great frameworks – reframing my focus.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/great-frameworks-reframing-my-focus./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/great-frameworks-reframing-my-focus./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The two most helpful frameworks that I&amp;rsquo;m working with right now are a brilliant piece on &lt;a href=&#34;http://circlesofwisdom.org/assets/Intervene%20in%20a%20System.htm&#34;&gt;places to intervene in a system&lt;/a&gt; by Donella Meadows and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ottoscharmer.com/&#34;&gt;theory u&lt;/a&gt; by Otto Scharmer. The Meadows piece has helped me articulate where I&amp;rsquo;m most drawn to invest myself (mindset shifts &amp;ndash; even more the process of doing so) and Scharmer&amp;rsquo;s work is a comprehensive model of the stages involved in creating a mindset shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurial Approach – exploratory presentation.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/entrepreneurial-approach-exploratory-presentation./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/entrepreneurial-approach-exploratory-presentation./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve done my quick first draft on exploring the entrepreneurial approach and its application. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/igniter-venture-buliding-approach-impact-focused-accelerated-deliberate-replicable/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to post it yet, but just had a great conversation with a coffee friend (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merchantsofgreencoffee.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshcoffeenetwork.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalwarmingcoffee.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that was prompted by this draft. Cheers to good conversations!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the train</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/on-the-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/on-the-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Have been meaning to post this for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I was on a train that &amp;lsquo;had an altercation&amp;rsquo; with a person who apparently had decided to part with the world. When the announcement came across the PA that there was a fatality and that we would be delayed at least 2 hours, there was a large outcry from many of the passengers in my car that went something like this: &amp;ldquo;Oh man&amp;hellip; now I&amp;rsquo;m going to be late. What an inconvenience. This sucks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P&gt;E&gt;P</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/pep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/pep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve just come up with a simple image that I&amp;rsquo;m starting work with in my exploration of how to apply the entrepreneurial approach in service of restoring balance among people and the planet. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m seeing the process as a balance of push and pull with the space in between those being where opportunity and innovation emerges, and what I see as the work of the entrepreneurial process. It&amp;rsquo;s about creating that space and creating the conditions of push and pull that prompt what&amp;rsquo;s most helpful to emerge.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Rh-DZN8feLI/AAAAAAAAAAo/LX_7bImStiw/s1600-h/PEP.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Rh-DZN8feLI/AAAAAAAAAAo/LX_7bImStiw/s320/PEP.gif&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5052901776196335794 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling up the social finance marketplace in Canada.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/scaling-up-the-social-finance-marketplace-in-canada./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/scaling-up-the-social-finance-marketplace-in-canada./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting map from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.xigi.net/&lt;/a&gt; giving an overview of the latest initiative I&amp;rsquo;m co-creating. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked-out [xigi]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}.net&amp;hellip; take a look. A very interesting tool that&amp;rsquo;s growing quickly and has the potential to make a significant contribution to the global marketplace that invests in good. Anyone else get the feeling that this &amp;lsquo;marketplace&amp;rsquo; is really starting to take off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center; border-style: solid; border-width: 2px; border-color: blue; width: 200px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/index.php?gallery=1&amp;amp;map_id=32&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/uploads/xigimap_53.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;200px&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border-style: none;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My latest presentations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/my-latest-presentations./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/my-latest-presentations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Here are the latest presentations on the directions that are really interesting me right now. Take a look and send me any &lt;strong&gt;thoughts, comments, connections&lt;/strong&gt;. It grows and gains momentum with the attention of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accelerating the collective potential of individual change:&lt;/strong&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systematically applying the entrepreneurial approach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(UPDATED: April 19, 2007)&lt;br&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For benefit/community interest corporations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/for-benefit/community-interest-corporations./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/for-benefit/community-interest-corporations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The U.K. and soon the U.S. are putting together some great new hybrid models that look to engage the power of the capital markets in ventures that are created strictly in community interest. Take a look &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialenterprise.org.uk/Page.aspx?SP=1626&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a primer on the U.K. model and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/2007/02/22/mixing-mission-and-business-new-legal-forms-for-social-enterprise.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for launch pad to some of the U.S. work. Seeing the evolution of markets is a wonderful thing.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How authentic are you?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/how-authentic-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/how-authentic-are-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I just saw two interesting perspectives on connecting with what people care about. One of which is from client/collaborator &lt;a href=&#34;www.communicopia.com&#34;&gt;Communicopia&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/communicopia-iima-core-values-presentation&#34;&gt;this presentation&lt;/a&gt; and one is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.canadianbusiness.com/entrepreneur/sales_marketing/article.jsp?content=20070228_103116_5132&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in Canadian Business titled &amp;ldquo;Sell More by Creating Desire&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme is something I&amp;rsquo;m seeing more and more everyday particularly with the steady growth in popularity of social and environmental justice issues. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a company giving to a charity, creating a new product, or simply your own efforts to make a difference the durability and success are anchored in authenticity &amp;mdash; is it connected with the true nature of who you are as an organization or an individual?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the Collective Potential for Positive Change</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/accelerating-the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/accelerating-the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve just come across &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net&#34;&gt;www.slideshare.net&lt;/a&gt; and figured I&amp;rsquo;d try it using the latest version of the presentation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that I&amp;rsquo;m working with on the topic of accelerating the collection potential for positive change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this works&amp;hellip; and of course&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in feedback!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To the point… .</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/to-the-point-./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/to-the-point-./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
So this is what it comes down to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m exploring:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; ways to accelerate the individual capacity for positive change&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; ways to systematically, repeatably, apply the [entrepreneurial]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-corrected} approach toward environmental and social justice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principles I&amp;rsquo;m working from:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; The community holds the knowledge and experience.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; We facilitate their wisdom&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; We orchestrate their solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; if anyone has anything that maybe relevant (connections, docs, [initiatives]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-corrected}, etc.) to either of those areas that I&amp;rsquo;m exploring, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about them!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s got my attention.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/whats-got-my-attention./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/whats-got-my-attention./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
This process all started with me trying to get a feeling for two things:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; what am I uniquely able to do?&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; where do I want to focus my attention?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course those questions both prompt deeper questions &amp;ndash; which have been a big part of my journey lately &amp;ndash; but what I came up with that best captured it for me was the statement I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing: co-creating entities and initiatives in service of restoring balance among people and the planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future of organizations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-future-of-organizations./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2007 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-future-of-organizations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I just read a very interesting paper called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gan-net.net&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Future of Global Action Networks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (look for the document link a little ways down the page). What was interesting, was not necessarily the discussion of &amp;ldquo;Global Action Networks&amp;rdquo; but the underlying observations on how they operate and are setup. From my perspective, these approaches to organizations are going to be fundamentally important to the most relevant organizations of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has done or wants to do a summary of this document please let me know. I&amp;rsquo;d love to post it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s just money.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/its-just-money./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2007 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/its-just-money./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Well, I&amp;rsquo;m back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting start to the year and I&amp;rsquo;m starting to test some of the examples of this &amp;lsquo;model&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing and have actually, [unbeknown ]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-corrected}to me, wound up in a project that actually represents the model I&amp;rsquo;m developing (funny how that happens). I guess that&amp;rsquo;s partly because, as with most things, the model isn&amp;rsquo;t really new. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially just an intentional version of the common [entrepreneurial]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-corrected} approach. What seems to strike people most however is not the approach but the idea that the seed financing happens before there&amp;rsquo;s even an idea&amp;hellip; where there is only an intention for some sort of result or impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for the conversation! AGAIN!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Following up on my conversation post earlier&amp;hellip; I just got off the phone with another connection by the same person. The &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; happened again. This time I consciously took my learning from the previous post into the call and it took the conversation even further. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not really magic after all. My gratitude for the relationships I have just continues to grow. Thanks!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free services!!!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/free-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/free-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I was just helping a client do a last-minute media launch for something we expected to get a lot of traffic. Naturally I asked one of my long-time communications collaborators to help out. He agreed and we agreed on costs etc&amp;hellip; quick/fair/reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; as sometimes happens it didn&amp;rsquo;t come off as we expected and the results were disappointing. I just got a note about this from my colleague with the additional comment:\&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for the conversation!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Yesterday, I had a great conversation with someone that a friend/colleague/client thought might be a worthwhile introduction. And he was right. The conversation was enjoyable and very helpful. Similar to the conversation a couple of weeks ago that had me step back from the full-blown financial model and pitch deck to trying to apply the venturing process I am suggesting to the creation of what I&amp;rsquo;m building&amp;hellip; this one prompted another launch path that fit with both my entrepreneurial drive to &amp;lsquo;push&amp;rsquo; something forward, and also with the process I&amp;rsquo;m suggesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking the talk.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/walking-the-talk./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 05:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/walking-the-talk./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
So here I start&amp;hellip; in that period where an idea shifts, changes, grows, implodes&amp;hellip; and hopefully emerges better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some time this summer vowing not to make any commitments to any project until the fall&amp;hellip; and to not launch anything new on my own. In September I emerged refreshed from some time with family and some time with myself&amp;hellip; alone. The product of that time was my best attempt to describe what it is that I do and where I want to focus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
