<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Venture on Lewwwk</title>
    <link>https://lewwwk.com/tags/venture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Venture on Lewwwk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:28:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lewwwk.com/tags/venture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transformative Ventures</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: entry-content
Putting a &amp;lsquo;dent a in the universe&amp;rsquo; is the goal of many mission-driven ventures. Those that succeed will create the new normals for a more vibrant, sustainable, and inclusive future. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt;, we call them transformative ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking and achieving transformative impact is what we are most interested in. It&amp;rsquo;s also different than achieving incremental improvements, regardless of how valuable they might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring more colour to the differences, and what we&amp;rsquo;re most excited about in the years ahead, we&amp;rsquo;re pleased to share our perspective on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation Hotspots</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc/&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt; we are interested in how ventures can create a better future, a future that is more vibrant, prosperous, and sustainable. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;re highlighting a few areas where we see extraordinary opportunity for progress in the next few years as we emerge from the pandemic. While these overlap with existing transition pathways, and will evolve over time, they focus in on certain characteristics of the types of innovations we think have particular momentum and potential for transformative impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the Frontiers – A simple guide.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venturing on the frontiers is about the early stages of taking on big challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s a space where conventional models to planning and management prove ineffective. It&amp;rsquo;s the place where entrepeneurs trust their &amp;lsquo;gut&amp;rsquo; and face the challenges with an unrelenting push forward. And it&amp;rsquo;s the place from which the greatest change can come about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The definitive definitions of venturing!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
One of the surprising things that I came out of my latest exploration into the frontiers of venturing and venture investing is a set of definitions. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not one that likes to debate definitions ad infinitum but I found I needed to clarify things to be able to have meaningful conversations going forward. So here, is what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with&amp;hellip; for now (I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this definitions as the evolve so feel free to check-back or link here for reference).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics of the frontier: complex ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The frontiers of venturing are the places where conventional venturing and planning approaches become least effective. It is the effective limit of conventional approaches to venturing that define the edge of the frontier with the deepest depths of the frontier being the pre-concept stage of a systemically focused venture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831.jpg?v=0&#34; title=&#34;Frontiers of venturing&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 10px 10px 0pt 0pt; float: left; width: 286px; height: 265px;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
Conventional approaches loose effectiveness the earlier a venture is in the development phase because of increasing ambiguity.  The less that is known the harder it is to do linear modeling and planning.  Choices made continually reduce ambiguity as the venture moves along the development and into the realm where conventional planning approaches can be effectively used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
