<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Lewwwk</title>
    <link>https://lewwwk.com/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Lewwwk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:38:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lewwwk.com/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coordinating residential energy efficiency, onchain.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/coordinating-residential-energy-efficiency-onchain./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 18:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/coordinating-residential-energy-efficiency-onchain./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been close to the challenges of shifting the built environment toward NetZero for a couple of decades now. First in venture capital, then as a founder in the residential thermal energy domain, and since as a board member of Windfall Ecology Centre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal has always been to simplify and incentivize changes in behaviour and technology adoption. Turns out, massively multiplayer coordination challenges can prove to be incredibly sticky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate X</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/climate-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 15:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/climate-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The impacts of climate change are everywhere, giving rise to new risks and accelerating the need to adapt our physical infrastructure and societies. Regulators are introducing new regulations to disclose those risks to protect the financial system. Investors are adjusting portfolios and adopting new products to accelerate infrastructure adaptation to manage risk and returns. Governments are planning large-scale investments into new infrastructure to prepare for an uncertain future. People are wondering if they are safe and secure where they live and work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two economies, for our future.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/two-economies-for-our-future./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 13:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/two-economies-for-our-future./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
As the twin crises of climate and inequality continue to ripple through society, we have a growing imperative to address them both. If either continues unabated, neither can be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a venture perspective, we are starting to think of the set of solutions that venture can contribute as economies of Transition and Cooperation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Transition Economy&lt;/strong&gt; recognizes the need to accelerate decarbonization and adaptation. It is not about climate or environment, but rather the solutions that allow us to build a future in harmony with both (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://calwave.energy&#34;&gt;CalWave&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://leap.energy&#34;&gt;Leap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wren.co&#34;&gt;Wren&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformative Ventures</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformative-ventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: entry-content
Putting a &amp;lsquo;dent a in the universe&amp;rsquo; is the goal of many mission-driven ventures. Those that succeed will create the new normals for a more vibrant, sustainable, and inclusive future. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt;, we call them transformative ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking and achieving transformative impact is what we are most interested in. It&amp;rsquo;s also different than achieving incremental improvements, regardless of how valuable they might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bring more colour to the differences, and what we&amp;rsquo;re most excited about in the years ahead, we&amp;rsquo;re pleased to share our perspective on:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation Hotspots</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/transformation-hotspots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
At &lt;a href=&#34;https://possibilian.vc/&#34;&gt;Possibilian&lt;/a&gt; we are interested in how ventures can create a better future, a future that is more vibrant, prosperous, and sustainable. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;re highlighting a few areas where we see extraordinary opportunity for progress in the next few years as we emerge from the pandemic. While these overlap with existing transition pathways, and will evolve over time, they focus in on certain characteristics of the types of innovations we think have particular momentum and potential for transformative impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world after COVID-19: A framework for considering the future.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-world-after-covid-19-a-framework-for-considering-the-future./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 21:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-world-after-covid-19-a-framework-for-considering-the-future./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image size-large&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- Image unavailable --&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR: We already see signs for how our world might change, we just can&amp;rsquo;t be sure which changes will stick. There&amp;rsquo;s a wide range of possible futures ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&#34;https://airtable.com/shrg6MFWQZRVrBgtF&#34;&gt;collecting a range of perspectives&lt;/a&gt; on the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic, to get a sense of what the world might look like after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lucidchart.com/invitations/accept/48331db0-7f52-4230-a362-306b2641bf70&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;m at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-this-so-disruptive&#34; class=&#34;wp-block-heading&#34;&gt;Why is this so disruptive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systemic failures as a result of the pandemic are impacting daily life and order. The speed and severity of these breakdowns is leading to rapid testing of what were previously &amp;lsquo;radical&amp;rsquo; ideas. This creates an opening for meaningfully different futures to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Capabilities, Behaviours, and Systems: How ventures change the world.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/new-capabilities-behaviours-and-systems-how-ventures-change-the-world./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 19:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/new-capabilities-behaviours-and-systems-how-ventures-change-the-world./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
A few weeks ago I started sharing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/possibilian/How-we-think-about-ventures-and-the-future-f248f1e4c7d44e15803c24b009648251&#34;&gt;how we think about the transformative potential of ventures&lt;/a&gt;, or in other words, what&amp;rsquo;s the potential for a company to &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to predict if any venture will actually &amp;lsquo;change the world&amp;rsquo;, we can be sure that if it does, it will have done so through some combination of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introducing meaningful new capabilities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sparking a change in behaviour;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enabling new systems of people, things, and information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Twitter as a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An experiment in describing transformative potential in venture.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/an-experiment-in-describing-transformative-potential-in-venture./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 21:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/an-experiment-in-describing-transformative-potential-in-venture./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: {#container role=&amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the bottleneck: The shift from social to systemic impact</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/breaking-the-bottleneck-the-shift-from-social-to-systemic-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 15:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/breaking-the-bottleneck-the-shift-from-social-to-systemic-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/r6iPtc&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Igniter - Systemic Incubation Model&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8682/16468978269_f4ac1315ef_z.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; fetchpriority=&amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just read &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/trisml&#34;&gt;Tris Lumley&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ssireview.org/blog/entry/transforming_our_anti_social_sector&#34;&gt;Transforming our Anti-Social Sector&lt;/a&gt; along side three posts by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dompotter&#34;&gt;Dom Potter&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/story-social-investment-dom-potter&#34;&gt;The Story of Social Investment&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/accelerating-collaborative-collective-startups-dom-potter&#34;&gt;Rethinking how we support impact driven organizations to start-up&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/collaborative-collective-investment-social-change-dom-potter&#34;&gt;Collaborative and collective impact for social change&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, they tell a story of how our best approaches to investing in impact-first ventures are falling short. Incremental improvements to what we are doing are not enough. At the same time, the answer is not in trying to replicate the financial-first startup support ecosystem. Nor is it likely to be &amp;lsquo;something in the middle&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are you doing?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/how-are-you-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/how-are-you-doing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
It&amp;rsquo;s a simple question and it&amp;rsquo;s the heart of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pineHQ.com&#34;&gt;Pine&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s daily check-in. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.com&#34;&gt;we&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;ve been building Pine over the last six weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve answered it about 120 times. This is my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning I&amp;rsquo;d look at the question, not sure where to start. Often I&amp;rsquo;d quickly tap in a few words. Sometimes those words turned into paragraphs. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d check-in with a simple emoticon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, I started noticing things throughout the day. Little thoughts. Sudden reactions. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d reach for Pine and tap them in. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;d just pause and watch them play out. And then, it hit me. There was a pattern in my responses, a common theme lurking below the surface that had been shaping my days. Now it&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;ve even done much to change that pattern yet, but simply noticing it lessened its influence and my days are noticeably flowing a little more lightly. Not bad for a simple question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the potential of digital for impact</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/reflections-on-the-potential-of-digital-for-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/reflections-on-the-potential-of-digital-for-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Digital technologies are increasingly integral to understanding and enabling social innovations. Whether it is as a beneficiary of a social service, a pioneering entrepreneur, or an intermediary, researcher or policy maker, we all increasingly depend on digital technology in our work. As these digital technologies spread to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com/post7517&#34;&gt;link every person and every thing&lt;/a&gt;{rel=&amp;ldquo;noopener noreferrer&amp;rdquo; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;}, we are beginning to see how digital technology is central to our ability to gather data, engage others, and ultimately create the systems of our future. Indeed, it is impossible to think doing so without it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developers seeking adventure.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/developers-seeking-adventure./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 13:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/developers-seeking-adventure./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
We&amp;rsquo;re looking for the next adventure at &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.com&#34;&gt;Igniter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a small team of developers, facilitators and entrepreneurs. We build web applications that invite connection, nurture relationship, and build understanding. Our approach is friendly and designed to facilitate flow. We start simply, work quickly and care about what we&amp;rsquo;re crafting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our short time together, we&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to quietly craft some great solutions with some ambitious partners:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yourquestions.mcdonalds.ca&#34;&gt;Our Food. Your Questions.&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://tribalddb.com&#34;&gt;Tribal DDB&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcdonalds.ca&#34;&gt;McDonald&amp;rsquo;s Canada&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://waittimes.cihi.ca&#34;&gt;Wait Times. For Priority Procedures in Canada.&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;http://normativedesign.com&#34;&gt;Normative Design&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cihi.ca&#34;&gt;Candian Institute for Health Information&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love working with creative agencies and organizations that are shaping the future. If that sounds like you, we&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A crack in the dam – opening a new domain.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-crack-in-the-dam-opening-a-new-domain./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-crack-in-the-dam-opening-a-new-domain./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jef_safi/225426814/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/88/225426814_902dff2512_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jef_safi/225426814/&#34;&gt;Rhizoming the plane of emergence 2.0 . .&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/jef_safi/&#34;&gt;jεƒ saƒı&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been in the works for awhile and I now think we&amp;rsquo;re really starting to make a connection between web tech (2.0+), venture investing, social innovation. That connection is going to unleash some tremendous innovations and a surge in the activity directly working on the challenges facing our civilization. It feels like the emergence of a new domain that will take some very different approaches to change and influencing the course of civilization. It seems inspired by open source, technology innovation, financial risk taking, a venturing culture, and now a deepening and deeply felt realization that there are more important tasks to tend to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An open quote from Michael Edwards</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/an-open-quote-from-michael-edwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/an-open-quote-from-michael-edwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&#34;font-family: arial; font-weight: normal; font-style: italic;font-size:78%;&#34; id=&#34;cross-posted-from-my-tumblog&#34;&gt;[Cross posted from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;tumblog&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/39078854/open-more-radical-innovations-in-ownership-and&#34;&gt;Open: &amp;ldquo;more radical innovations in ownership and production that change the basis on which markets currently work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the conclusion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://justanotheremperor.org&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just Another Emperor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Edwards, he poses the above quote which I think is a great description of what &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; is actually playing at. Full context here: &amp;ldquo;Philanthrocapitalism offers one way of increasing the social value of the market, but there are other routes that could offer equal or better results in changing the way the economic surplus is produced, distributed and used: the traditional route that uses external pressure, taxation and regulation; the philanthrocapitalist route that changes internal incentives and gives a little more back through foundations and corporate social repsonsibility; and the more radical innovations in ownership and production that change the basis in which markets work. We don&amp;rsquo;t know which of these routes carries the greatest long term potential, though all of them rely on civil society as a vehicle for innovation, accountability, influence and modified consumption, and especially for getting us from reformist to transformational solutions.&amp;rdquo;
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benevolent dictators in the open movement</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/benevolent-dictators-in-the-open-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/benevolent-dictators-in-the-open-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SFkZZoVM3KI/AAAAAAAAAC4/kfsjLRe1l40/s1600-h/254908846_c8a5982675_m.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp1.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/SFkZZoVM3KI/AAAAAAAAAC4/kfsjLRe1l40/s320/254908846_c8a5982675_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5213225971771825314 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;quot;}One of the interesting things coming out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/06/open-everything-toronto-reflection.html&#34;&gt;OPEN everything (Toronto)&lt;/a&gt; was the idea that open projects are driven by what we were calling &amp;lsquo;benevolent dictators&amp;rsquo;. That phrase, while abrasive to some, seems to be resonating in a number of different conversations that I and others are having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it seems to do is counter the notion that open is a touchy-[feely]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}, everyone has to agree, happy place where everyone gets along. At the same time it reinforces the important and evolving role of leadership. What I&amp;rsquo;m starting to try and tease out is what are the qualities of open leadership that we&amp;rsquo;re really getting at? And which of those are core values &amp;ndash; and which are situational reactions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenEverything opens today!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-opens-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/openeverything-opens-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Well, it was only a few months ago when &lt;a href=&#34;http://communicopia.net/who-we-are/our-team/jason-mogus&#34;&gt;Jason [Mogus]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://commonspace.typepad.com/about.html&#34;&gt;Mark [Surman]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt; and I chatted on this concept of the event series that is now underway. It started as an exploration as to a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://webofchange.com&#34;&gt;Web Of Change&lt;/a&gt; event at Hollyhock this year and Mark has taken it to what is going to be an amazing series that is going to push our thinking and the thinking of the &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo; community even further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some related links – adding on to another conversation.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/some-related-links-adding-on-to-another-conversation./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/some-related-links-adding-on-to-another-conversation./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I commented on Fred Wilson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.blogs.com/a_vc/2008/05/looking-forward.html&#34;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/a&gt; post yesterday and he [reblogged]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} a part of my comment in his [tumblog]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} &lt;a href=&#34;http://fredwilson.vc/post/34956572#disqus_thread&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. [Tt&amp;rsquo;s]{#SPELLING_ERROR_2 .blsp-spelling-error} been generating a few emails to me so for those that are interested, here are a few other links that follow that theme&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; A few of us are convening an event that is digging deeper into that mindset that riffs off open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://openeverything.net&#34;&gt;[openeverything]{#SPELLING_ERROR_3 .blsp-spelling-error}.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; [Ervin]{#SPELLING_ERROR_4 .blsp-spelling-error} [Laszlo&amp;rsquo;s]{#SPELLING_ERROR_5 .blsp-spelling-error} &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or.html&#34;&gt;[Macroshift]{#SPELLING_ERROR_6 .blsp-spelling-error}&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; a book about the evolution of civilization and the interplay of technology and mindsets (my highlights and links to the book &amp;ndash; additional post &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/11/rest-of-macroshift.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; A post of mine on this phase we are in that I&amp;rsquo;m calling &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/05/great-remix.html&#34;&gt;the Great Remix&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Additional posts &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/05/doing-differently-in-great-remix.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/11/rest-of-macroshift.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/higlights-from-of-enterprise-viable.html&#34;&gt;Stafford Beer&amp;rsquo;s work&lt;/a&gt; on information design of systems in an organizational context (my highlights and links to his book and work)
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Tech Training – June 22-24, 2008</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-tech-training-june-22-24-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-tech-training-june-22-24-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/socialtechtraining&#34; title=&#34;SocialTech Training&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SocialTech Training&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://webofchange.com/sites/webofchange.com/files/images/stt_badge5.gif&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/socialtechtraining&#34;&gt;Social Tech Training&lt;/a&gt; is happening this June in Toronto.  Here&amp;rsquo;s the link and a quick blurb.  Check-it out and sign-up if it catches your eye. Coming from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webofchange.com&#34;&gt;Web of Change&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marsdd.com/&#34;&gt;MaRS&lt;/a&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s bound to be an excellent event!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::::: {}
::: {}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {}
No one working in social change these days can afford to ignore the opportunities offered by the web. Most organizations get stuck, though, on &amp;ldquo;How do we do it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Where do we start?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Who can help us?&amp;rdquo; Interest in high, but the talent pool of people equipped to understand, prioritize, and implement these tools and ideas remains limited.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Bets n’ chips” – Implications for investors on the frontiers.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/bets-n-chips-implications-for-investors-on-the-frontiers./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 21:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/bets-n-chips-implications-for-investors-on-the-frontiers./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seem to be two types of bets that investors make when doing a deal. A bet on the team. A bet on the plan. The closer to the frontiers (early stages and deep change) the greater the emphasis is on the team. And rightly so. We all know that plans don&amp;rsquo;t last on the frontiers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Gettin’ lucky” – implications for ventures on the frontiers.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-lucky-implications-for-ventures-on-the-frontiers./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-lucky-implications-for-ventures-on-the-frontiers./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the gist of this image &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2008/02/venturing-on-frontiers-simple-guide.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Now I&amp;rsquo;m turning to the implications for venturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply the essence of venturing is a process. A process of creating spaces for things to happen (some call it &amp;rsquo;luck&amp;rsquo;). The simpler and more accessible the space, the easier it is to get people engaged and get things done (some would say &amp;rsquo;the luckier you get&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the Frontiers – A simple guide.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontiers-a-simple-guide./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
::: {style=&amp;ldquo;float: right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34; title=&#34;photo sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2135/2247912561_ec56e3d2f5_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border: 2px solid rgb(0, 0, 0);&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/michaellewkowitz/2247912561/&#34;&gt;Venturing on the Frontiers &amp;ndash; A simple guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Originally uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/michaellewkowitz/&#34;&gt;Michael Lewkowitz&lt;/a&gt; ]{style=&amp;ldquo;margin-top: 0px;font-size:0;&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venturing on the frontiers is about the early stages of taking on big challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s a space where conventional models to planning and management prove ineffective. It&amp;rsquo;s the place where entrepeneurs trust their &amp;lsquo;gut&amp;rsquo; and face the challenges with an unrelenting push forward. And it&amp;rsquo;s the place from which the greatest change can come about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing and venture investing on the frontiers – in simple terms.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-venture-investing-on-the-frontiers-in-simple-terms./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-and-venture-investing-on-the-frontiers-in-simple-terms./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked a few times about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on in simple terms. Not always easy for me &amp;ndash; but here goes top-of-mind while riding the train&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[My focus is on venturing and venture investing &amp;lsquo;on the frontiers&amp;rsquo;. ]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venturing is about organizing and directing resources toward a purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;venture investing is about improving the capacity of ventures to achieve their purpose (or certain milestones along the way)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;on the frontiers&amp;rsquo; means the places where conventional ways of doing things are least effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work is focused on being able to systematically improve ventures and venture investors operating on the frontiers. My belief is that by focusing here, practices can be developed and demonstrated that will themselves become conventional in time and thereby move &amp;rsquo;the frontiers&amp;rsquo; greatly increasing our society&amp;rsquo;s ability and capacity to take on our civilization&amp;rsquo;s greatest challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Social’-lingo</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-lingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Many things have been picking up the &amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo; modifier lately. Here are some of the ones I&amp;rsquo;m encountering and what I think they mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the modifier [&amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo;]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modifies the following word to the focus of serving a social (and/or environmental) benefit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[tech]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technology employed for social benefit (most commonly digital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[change]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concerned generally with societal change and how it happens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[innovation]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;innovations and the process of innovating solutions that deliver or enable social change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social-[venture]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-weight: bold;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘evil’ in exchanges.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-evil-in-exchanges./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-evil-in-exchanges./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Exchanges are a hot topic in the social capital markets. They are appealing in the sense of the efficiency they promise. Efficiency is good &amp;ndash; and it also has a dark side. This dark-side, which I&amp;rsquo;m considering the &amp;lsquo;inherent evil&amp;rsquo; in exchanges, is their tendency to disconnect/dissociate the &amp;lsquo;buyer&amp;rsquo; from the &amp;lsquo;seller&amp;rsquo;. It comes out in things like the sub-prime mess and rogue traders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we get the benefits of this &amp;lsquo;masterpiece&amp;rsquo; of capitalism?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This biggering is buggering… a call for a new vision of ‘prosperity’.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/this-biggering-is-buggering-a-call-for-a-new-vision-of-prosperity./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/this-biggering-is-buggering-a-call-for-a-new-vision-of-prosperity./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I attended a session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sustainableprosperity.ca/&#34;&gt;Sustainable Prosperity&lt;/a&gt; last week and was left with a pretty big realization that evolved for me into what blurted out in a strategy session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windfallcentre.ca/&#34;&gt;Windfall Ecology Centre&lt;/a&gt; on Friday as..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This [BIGGERING]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} is buggering&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is inspired by Dr. Seuss&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Lorax-Classic-Seuss-Dr/dp/0394823370/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1201558467&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The [Lorax]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error}&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, (see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniter.tumblr.com/post/24907301&#34;&gt;specific quotes here&lt;/a&gt;), but it also refers to a growing realization that the thing that economy is based on &amp;ndash; continuously increasing consumption &amp;ndash; is reaching a breaking point. To be clear, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a recession inspired &amp;lsquo;people aren&amp;rsquo;t going to consume as much anymore&amp;rsquo; statement, it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;lsquo;if people consume anywhere near what we&amp;rsquo;re consuming we&amp;rsquo;re all screwed&amp;rsquo; statement. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.storyofstuff.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Story of Stuff&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freerangemedia.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Free Range Media&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tides.org/&#34;&gt;Tides Foundation&lt;/a&gt; makes a simple and decent case for that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The definitive definitions of venturing!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-definitive-definitions-of-venturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
One of the surprising things that I came out of my latest exploration into the frontiers of venturing and venture investing is a set of definitions. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not one that likes to debate definitions ad infinitum but I found I needed to clarify things to be able to have meaningful conversations going forward. So here, is what I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with&amp;hellip; for now (I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this definitions as the evolve so feel free to check-back or link here for reference).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd sourcing in venturing</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/crowd-sourcing-in-venturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/crowd-sourcing-in-venturing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Just saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidcrow.ca/article/1812/crowd-powered-capital&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; tipping me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cambrianhouse.com/vencorps/&#34;&gt;VenCorps&lt;/a&gt; which seems to be a venture fund using &amp;lsquo;crowd sourcing&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be interested to see how it goes and expect they will do well by essentially &amp;lsquo;amping up the network&amp;rsquo;. My guess is that they will be better at dealing with ambiguity (related to progressing along stage of development) in ventures but I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see if it will help them deal with complexity (related to depth of systemic change). The thing that gives me a sense that they won&amp;rsquo;t be as effective here is the military style they are coming out with. That to me indicates a very linear, command and control approach which is not effective in dealing with complexity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giddy-up: getting better on the frontier.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2008 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/giddy-up-getting-better-on-the-frontier./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Coming out of this first inquiry I&amp;rsquo;m left with new definitions for venture, venturing, and venturer and also a simplistic grouping that the process of venturing essentially requires agreement, action, and governance. It is important to note that these are a set of observations and interpretations that will continue to be evolved in practice. As such they represent a starting point for a concerted effort to &amp;lsquo;get better at venturing and investing on the frontiers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gettin’ it goin’ without goin’ under: cohesion and incipient instability.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/gettin-it-goin-without-goin-under-cohesion-and-incipient-instability./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
With requisite attention being held a natural propulsion will emerge.  The act of managing and nurturing that propulsion is attended to with a focus on cohesion and being proactively aware of the emergence of incipient instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts are addressed in depth in Stafford Beer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viable_System_Model&#34;&gt;viable system model&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/10/higlights-from-of-enterprise-viable.html&#34;&gt;my reflections here&lt;/a&gt; on reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Enterprise-Classic-Beer/dp/0471948373/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1199076860&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Heart of Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;) and are really about holding the tension between future (vision), and here and now (operations) [see last post for &lt;a href=&#34;http://lewwwk.com2007/12/venturing-on-frontier-requisite.html&#34;&gt;more on requisite attention&lt;/a&gt;]. Cohesion has a lot to do with articulating purpose as so well described by[ ]{style=&amp;ldquo;text-decoration: underline;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_C._Collins&#34;&gt;Collins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_Porras&#34;&gt;Porras&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://harvardbusinessonline.hbsp.harvard.edu/b02/en/common/item_detail.jhtml?id=410X&amp;amp;referral=2340&#34;&gt;Building Your Company&amp;rsquo;s Vision&lt;/a&gt;. And incipient instability is about monitoring trends in financials, plan performance, and relationship status (after all, ventures are systems, concentrated bundles of relationships), and then spotting changes that indicate that something is becoming instable in a way that could harm the cohesion of the system as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venturing on the frontier: requisite attention</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/venturing-on-the-frontier-requisite-attention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Venturing on the frontiers requires distinctly holding attention on two discrete aspects of any venture:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Productive, iterative, exploration of the complexity dynamic&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; Core venture viability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple to say but in practice, venturers who aren&amp;rsquo;t stuck in perpetual analysis and thought, are pulled toward focusing on linear, or hopefully exponential, growth of the most promising aspect at hand particularly after attracting professional investment capital. Stop thinking and just do it right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dynamics of the frontier: complex ambiguity</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-dynamics-of-the-frontier-complex-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The frontiers of venturing are the places where conventional venturing and planning approaches become least effective. It is the effective limit of conventional approaches to venturing that define the edge of the frontier with the deepest depths of the frontier being the pre-concept stage of a systemically focused venture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831.jpg?v=0&#34; title=&#34;Frontiers of venturing&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 10px 10px 0pt 0pt; float: left; width: 286px; height: 265px;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
Conventional approaches loose effectiveness the earlier a venture is in the development phase because of increasing ambiguity.  The less that is known the harder it is to do linear modeling and planning.  Choices made continually reduce ambiguity as the venture moves along the development and into the realm where conventional planning approaches can be effectively used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social blogging</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/social-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2007 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/social-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
[[]{#formatbar_CreateLink .on onmousedown=&amp;ldquo;CheckFormatting(event);FormatbarButton(&amp;lsquo;richeditorframe&amp;rsquo;, this, 8);ButtonMouseDown(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseout=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOff(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseover=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOn(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseup=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;Link&amp;rdquo;}]{#formatbar_Buttons style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo;}[[]{#formatbar_CreateLink .on .down onmousedown=&amp;ldquo;CheckFormatting(event);FormatbarButton(&amp;lsquo;richeditorframe&amp;rsquo;, this, 8);ButtonMouseDown(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseout=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOff(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseover=&amp;ldquo;ButtonHoverOn(this);&amp;rdquo; onmouseup=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;rdquo; title=&amp;ldquo;Link&amp;rdquo;}]{#formatbar_Buttons style=&amp;ldquo;display: block;&amp;quot;}Fred Wilson at &lt;a href=&#34;www.unionsquareventures.com&#34;&gt;USV&lt;/a&gt; had &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.blogs.com/a_vc/2007/12/social-blogging.html&#34;&gt;a post&lt;/a&gt; exploring the differences in &lt;a href=&#34;www.twitter.com&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; from other things like blogs and social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure there are a lot of people reading this who think &amp;ldquo;how is this different than blogging?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d like to suggest that everyone try this&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macroshift (Ervin Laszlo) — Doomsday or Breakthrough?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or-breakthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/macroshift-ervin-laszlo-doomsday-or-breakthrough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;m only through the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ervin_L%C3%A1szl%C3%B3&#34;&gt;Ervin Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Macroshift-Navigating-Transformation-Sustainable-World/dp/1576751635/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/002-0269927-3836077?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1193681423&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Macroshift&lt;/a&gt;, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d better post these snippets before I get caught-up in the flow of the week.  I came across this through a client who pointed to this as the best description of what their work is responding to.  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more&amp;hellip; and know a few others that will feel the same way&amp;hellip; and am hoping more people will join those ranks. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Higlights from “Heart of Enterprise” — the Viable System Model</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/higlights-from-heart-of-enterprise-the-viable-system-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 20:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/higlights-from-heart-of-enterprise-the-viable-system-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
[&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working my way through this tome for a few weeks and have had a number of conversations around it. It&amp;rsquo;s by far the most valuable piece of work I&amp;rsquo;ve ever encountered on organizational design &amp;mdash; and for me a critical model in ventures that are on the venturing frontier (early concept stage and/or systemic co-creation &amp;mdash; see graph below).]{style=&amp;ldquo;font-size:100%;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/60514480@N00/1748323488/&#34; title=&#34;Efficacy of venturing and investing models and practices&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Efficacy of venturing and investing models and practices&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://static.flickr.com/2162/1748323488_3073d7a831_m.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A good point – enough with the debate on climate change.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-good-point-enough-with-the-debate-on-climate-change./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-good-point-enough-with-the-debate-on-climate-change./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::::: entry-content
This is a nice argument for stopping the debate on climate change and getting on with it.  I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in the only answer to be policy change but it is an important one.  The basic argument is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; we can&amp;rsquo;t know for certain whether or not we are impacting climate change or what will happen&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; we can only choose whether or not we are going to do something about it&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; that choice really comes down to an assessment of the risk in acting or not&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; if we act, worst case is economic downturn&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ndash; if we don&amp;rsquo;t act, worst case is economic downturn PLUS other global catashrophies&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dress code? Ugghhh…</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/dress-code-ugghhh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 20:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/dress-code-ugghhh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
As time goes on I increasingly consider clothing first and foremost about function and comfort. For me this means jeans as my primary leg wear and then anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t need ironing for my tops. And for footwear it&amp;rsquo;s either my Crocs or Blundstones for sheer practicality. For some client work though, I still feel the need to at least put on a &amp;lsquo;dress-shirt&amp;rsquo; and some other pants.  On rare occasion &amp;ndash; like the social finance forum &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ll break-out a suit. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The beauty of good online services — unfolding.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-beauty-of-good-online-services-unfolding./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-beauty-of-good-online-services-unfolding./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been actively trying different online services and tools lately, one of which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wesabe.com&#34;&gt;www.wesabe.com&lt;/a&gt;. It was a particularly interesting test for me as it deals with personal financial data (for most people one the most sensitive data streams) and I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long-time user of Microsoft Money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I found it interesting but it was an effort to use it. Well&amp;hellip; they just launched a firefox browser extension which makes my uploads even easier than they were with the version of Money I was using.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic interventions — the fun stuff!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/systemic-interventions-the-fun-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/systemic-interventions-the-fun-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve linked to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.developerdotstar.com/mag/articles/places_intervene_system.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; on the left, but can&amp;rsquo;t seem to say it enough&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donella Meadows&amp;rsquo; description of places to intervene in a system is the best guide I&amp;rsquo;ve come across for this stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily use it as a way to categorize the type or degree of systemic intervention an initiative is taking on but rather as a prompt to help me feel for the where an intervention may be most effective and what shifts may be prompted by the intervention being contemplated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts of systemic intervention.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/catalysts-of-systemic-intervention./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2007 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/catalysts-of-systemic-intervention./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work with some great folks that are doing/working on amazing regional transformations through a systems approach. It&amp;rsquo;s [occured]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error} to me that they&amp;rsquo;re using two [seperate]{#SPELLING_ERROR_1 .blsp-spelling-error} catalysts in making that happen. One is using financial capital and the other community empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our current society, financial capital is one of the most powerful constructs in society and for now and always the empowerment or uprising of community is the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The tension of the two stories.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/the-tension-of-the-two-stories./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/the-tension-of-the-two-stories./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
It&amp;rsquo;s becoming more and more clear to me that our society is going through a major and accelerating transformation from the currently established &amp;rsquo;linear&amp;rsquo; mindset toward a &amp;lsquo;systems&amp;rsquo; mindset. There are countless ways to describe it but it is increasingly evident and felt particularly among those who are working on solutions to address the growing social and ecologcial threats our society is facing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tension of those two models colliding is palpable. The art of bringing them together is beautiful. The potential for it is limited and spontaneous. It&amp;rsquo;s not always possible and it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes unexpectedly possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seed venturing toward systemic interventions – deal funnel: screening, conditions, and structuring.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/seed-venturing-toward-systemic-interventions-deal-funnel-screening-conditions-and-structuring./</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 18:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/seed-venturing-toward-systemic-interventions-deal-funnel-screening-conditions-and-structuring./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Seeding ventures focussed on systemic interventions needs to be come at with an approach that is grounded in systems thinking. Conventional wisdom in venture investment has come from theory and experiences often based in working with business systems that are working within and dependent on the current system itself. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that the earlier the stage of investment and the more oriented the venture is toward a systemic intervention the more &amp;lsquo;gut instinct&amp;rsquo; is used a guide to making investment decisions and supporting the growth and success of those ventures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Venturing Model</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/a-venturing-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 03:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/a-venturing-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to post on this for a while now. It&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot of my latest understanding of the venturing process. It&amp;rsquo;s early draft and the writing below is pretty much stream of consciousness but I&amp;rsquo;m being drawn to just get it out:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Ro8IMBZz5lI/AAAAAAAAAAw/KmGG5MgFhUc/s1600-h/iggy-ivm-v1a.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Ro8IMBZz5lI/AAAAAAAAAAw/KmGG5MgFhUc/s400/iggy-ivm-v1a.gif&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5084291506952726098 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;rdquo;}&lt;br&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re in an interesting point in history where there is a transition from a mindset based on seeking to understand the smallest components of things (reductionist thinking, command and control models, &amp;rsquo;the great clockwork&amp;rsquo;, world/problems as &amp;lsquo;complicated&amp;rsquo;) toward a mindset that looks at systems in terms of the relationships/context in order to understand them (systems, ecological, &amp;lsquo;complex&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online &gt; mobile/recovering &gt; present</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/online-mobile/recovering-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/online-mobile/recovering-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve been actively putting myself online&amp;hellip; or rather updating my online presences and trying out the tools to manage my online connections lately and having been finding myself being hyper connected and active while I&amp;rsquo;m at my computer. While I&amp;rsquo;m working I&amp;rsquo;m usually listening to music, have a variety of online tools open (google reader, basecamp, slideshare, etc.) while at the same time doing email and working on docs/presentations. When I&amp;rsquo;m in that mode I can be hyper productive&amp;hellip; but sometimes, like an hour ago, my nervous system screams &amp;lsquo;stop&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/emergence./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/emergence./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
After much prodding a picked up the book &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chapters.indigo.ca/books/item/books-978067931443/0679314431/Getting-to-Maybe-How-the-World-Is-Changed?ref=Search+Books%3a+%27getting+to+maybe%27&#34;&gt;Getting to Maybe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; and started reading it on the weekend. I have been pushing deeper into &amp;rsquo;the entrepreneurial approach&amp;rsquo; and working with the idea that it is more about the creating/holding the space for things to emerge. This morning I read the chapter called &amp;lsquo;Let It Find You&amp;rsquo; which is all about emergence. I am more convinced that in this element of entrepreneurship/social innovation is the &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; that can be amplified and applied to restoring balance among people and the planet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great frameworks – reframing my focus.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/great-frameworks-reframing-my-focus./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/great-frameworks-reframing-my-focus./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The two most helpful frameworks that I&amp;rsquo;m working with right now are a brilliant piece on &lt;a href=&#34;http://circlesofwisdom.org/assets/Intervene%20in%20a%20System.htm&#34;&gt;places to intervene in a system&lt;/a&gt; by Donella Meadows and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ottoscharmer.com/&#34;&gt;theory u&lt;/a&gt; by Otto Scharmer. The Meadows piece has helped me articulate where I&amp;rsquo;m most drawn to invest myself (mindset shifts &amp;ndash; even more the process of doing so) and Scharmer&amp;rsquo;s work is a comprehensive model of the stages involved in creating a mindset shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entrepreneurial Approach – exploratory presentation.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/entrepreneurial-approach-exploratory-presentation./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/entrepreneurial-approach-exploratory-presentation./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve done my quick first draft on exploring the entrepreneurial approach and its application. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/igniter-venture-buliding-approach-impact-focused-accelerated-deliberate-replicable/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to post it yet, but just had a great conversation with a coffee friend (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merchantsofgreencoffee.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshcoffeenetwork.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalwarmingcoffee.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that was prompted by this draft. Cheers to good conversations!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the train</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/on-the-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/on-the-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Have been meaning to post this for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I was on a train that &amp;lsquo;had an altercation&amp;rsquo; with a person who apparently had decided to part with the world. When the announcement came across the PA that there was a fatality and that we would be delayed at least 2 hours, there was a large outcry from many of the passengers in my car that went something like this: &amp;ldquo;Oh man&amp;hellip; now I&amp;rsquo;m going to be late. What an inconvenience. This sucks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P&gt;E&gt;P</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/pep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/pep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve just come up with a simple image that I&amp;rsquo;m starting work with in my exploration of how to apply the entrepreneurial approach in service of restoring balance among people and the planet. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m seeing the process as a balance of push and pull with the space in between those being where opportunity and innovation emerges, and what I see as the work of the entrepreneurial process. It&amp;rsquo;s about creating that space and creating the conditions of push and pull that prompt what&amp;rsquo;s most helpful to emerge.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Rh-DZN8feLI/AAAAAAAAAAo/LX_7bImStiw/s1600-h/PEP.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://bp0.blogger.com/_Ilyk7YpQhy0/Rh-DZN8feLI/AAAAAAAAAAo/LX_7bImStiw/s320/PEP.gif&#34;&gt;{#BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5052901776196335794 border=&amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;{onblur=&amp;ldquo;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;rdquo;}
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scaling up the social finance marketplace in Canada.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/scaling-up-the-social-finance-marketplace-in-canada./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/scaling-up-the-social-finance-marketplace-in-canada./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;:::: entry-content
Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting map from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.xigi.net/&lt;/a&gt; giving an overview of the latest initiative I&amp;rsquo;m co-creating. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked-out [xigi]{#SPELLING_ERROR_0 .blsp-spelling-error}.net&amp;hellip; take a look. A very interesting tool that&amp;rsquo;s growing quickly and has the potential to make a significant contribution to the global marketplace that invests in good. Anyone else get the feeling that this &amp;lsquo;marketplace&amp;rsquo; is really starting to take off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::: {style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center; border-style: solid; border-width: 2px; border-color: blue; width: 200px;&amp;rdquo;}
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/index.php?gallery=1&amp;amp;map_id=32&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/uploads/xigimap_53.jpg&#34;&gt;{decoding=&amp;ldquo;async&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;200px&amp;rdquo; style=&amp;ldquo;border-style: none;&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My latest presentations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/my-latest-presentations./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/my-latest-presentations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Here are the latest presentations on the directions that are really interesting me right now. Take a look and send me any &lt;strong&gt;thoughts, comments, connections&lt;/strong&gt;. It grows and gains momentum with the attention of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accelerating the collective potential of individual change:&lt;/strong&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systematically applying the entrepreneurial approach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(UPDATED: April 19, 2007)&lt;br&gt;
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For benefit/community interest corporations.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/for-benefit/community-interest-corporations./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/for-benefit/community-interest-corporations./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
The U.K. and soon the U.S. are putting together some great new hybrid models that look to engage the power of the capital markets in ventures that are created strictly in community interest. Take a look &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialenterprise.org.uk/Page.aspx?SP=1626&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a primer on the U.K. model and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xigi.net/2007/02/22/mixing-mission-and-business-new-legal-forms-for-social-enterprise.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for launch pad to some of the U.S. work. Seeing the evolution of markets is a wonderful thing.
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How authentic are you?</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/how-authentic-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2007 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/how-authentic-are-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I just saw two interesting perspectives on connecting with what people care about. One of which is from client/collaborator &lt;a href=&#34;www.communicopia.com&#34;&gt;Communicopia&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/communicopia-iima-core-values-presentation&#34;&gt;this presentation&lt;/a&gt; and one is in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.canadianbusiness.com/entrepreneur/sales_marketing/article.jsp?content=20070228_103116_5132&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in Canadian Business titled &amp;ldquo;Sell More by Creating Desire&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme is something I&amp;rsquo;m seeing more and more everyday particularly with the steady growth in popularity of social and environmental justice issues. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a company giving to a charity, creating a new product, or simply your own efforts to make a difference the durability and success are anchored in authenticity &amp;mdash; is it connected with the true nature of who you are as an organization or an individual?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the Collective Potential for Positive Change</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/accelerating-the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/accelerating-the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I&amp;rsquo;ve just come across &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net&#34;&gt;www.slideshare.net&lt;/a&gt; and figured I&amp;rsquo;d try it using the latest version of the presentation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/MichaelLewkowitz/the-collective-potential-for-positive-change/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that I&amp;rsquo;m working with on the topic of accelerating the collection potential for positive change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this works&amp;hellip; and of course&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in feedback!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for the conversation! AGAIN!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Following up on my conversation post earlier&amp;hellip; I just got off the phone with another connection by the same person. The &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; happened again. This time I consciously took my learning from the previous post into the call and it took the conversation even further. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not really magic after all. My gratitude for the relationships I have just continues to grow. Thanks!
:::&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free services!!!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/free-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/free-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
I was just helping a client do a last-minute media launch for something we expected to get a lot of traffic. Naturally I asked one of my long-time communications collaborators to help out. He agreed and we agreed on costs etc&amp;hellip; quick/fair/reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; as sometimes happens it didn&amp;rsquo;t come off as we expected and the results were disappointing. I just got a note about this from my colleague with the additional comment:\&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for the conversation!</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/thanks-for-the-conversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
Yesterday, I had a great conversation with someone that a friend/colleague/client thought might be a worthwhile introduction. And he was right. The conversation was enjoyable and very helpful. Similar to the conversation a couple of weeks ago that had me step back from the full-blown financial model and pitch deck to trying to apply the venturing process I am suggesting to the creation of what I&amp;rsquo;m building&amp;hellip; this one prompted another launch path that fit with both my entrepreneurial drive to &amp;lsquo;push&amp;rsquo; something forward, and also with the process I&amp;rsquo;m suggesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking the talk.</title>
      <link>https://lewwwk.com/walking-the-talk./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 05:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lewwwk.com/walking-the-talk./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;::: entry-content
So here I start&amp;hellip; in that period where an idea shifts, changes, grows, implodes&amp;hellip; and hopefully emerges better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some time this summer vowing not to make any commitments to any project until the fall&amp;hellip; and to not launch anything new on my own. In September I emerged refreshed from some time with family and some time with myself&amp;hellip; alone. The product of that time was my best attempt to describe what it is that I do and where I want to focus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
